Friday.
The best day of the week.
Okay, no more of that filter.
No phone, stop activating.
I really freaking hate that.
I need to fix that.
I've been saying that for a year now.
The voice from above, you're right.
This game has religious overtones and I'm just, you know, embracing it.
I'm fully in it.
Please play a thousand hours of Isaac.
Dude, I can't play a thousand hours.
Are you crazy?
I need sleep.
I can't do... I don't even have energy for like five hours of it.
Cheers.
Oh man, that's good.
Guys, it is actually Friday.
Something about it, man.
When you look out the window, you know, and you look at the sky, there's just something different.
It's like the universe knows that it's Friday.
Because everybody knows that the earth is the center of everything.
It is the most important part of the entire universe.
And the made-up customs that we organisms on this rock have made up are important, you know, and the universe respects that.
Oh man.
Can you do a modern Minecraft season?
Well, you're in luck because that's the plan.
The next season of Minecraft is 99% chance gonna be a modded one.
So yeah.
I don't know when that'll be though, but mods for sure.
There's a guy on YouTube that said he will make 10 Isaac videos and he's at 6,000 hours?
What?
So wait, he uploads videos with 1,300 hours runtime?
Or how does that work?
Isanti, I've recently noticed that some people in chat ask you what are your thoughts on the thing that I saw and forgot about?
It feels back CD because it's reminding you of things in game.
I mean, you don't need to delete the messages, I guess, because I'm not looking at the chat, right?
So it's fine.
People are allowed to spoil and stuff when when I'm playing.
That's totally cool.
I'm not looking at the chat anyway.
But if they're saying it while I'm looking at the chat, then maybe.
I just... let me figure it out, you know?
Yeah.
Another chess livestream?
Maybe.
I haven't had the... what do you call it?
The want, the need, the motivation to play any chess lately for some reason.
The Netherlands has like 7,000 Isaac episodes.
That's crazy.
I knew the Netherlandsers were crazy.
I mean, I thought, you know, they were all about the bikes, but it turns out it's all about the Isaacs.
Sorry, this is what I read.
I don't know what NL is.
What keyboard are you using?
I'm using a... what am I using?
A Wooting keyboard.
The cheapest one they have.
Whatever that is.
I think so, at least.
Wooting.
Northern Lance?
Northern Lion?
Okay, multiple people are saying Northern Lion.
I choose to believe that.
Wooting!
Yeah, it's a Wooting keyboard.
The Shaolin.
Not the backseat, but I think you're cool.
Thank you.
Although that was a bit of a risky read.
Sometimes when people say not the backseat, it's usually followed by a backseat.
Or when people on YouTube go, sorry, I don't mean to spoil, but...
and then it's just stop reading, because you know it's gonna be a spoiler.
You know, this is kind of funny.
The way that works.
I guess it's just a misunderstanding between what I consider a spoiler and what other people consider spoilers, you know?
A backseat is basically someone sitting in the back of the car telling me how to drive the car, you know?
Like, let me drive!
I took the driver's license exam, except I actually didn't.
But let me let me learn it anyway on my own.
Yeah, exactly.
I'm not gonna tell you who emailed me spoilers.
Let's just say maybe five different people did it, maybe four.
I don't remember the exact number.
And some of them did it multiple times.
Yeah, yeah, it's crazy.
I'm not gonna say, I mean, it's so obvious when they're trying to do it, so I'm not really reading them, you know?
I mean, you can just glance at it and you know it's a spoiler.
I don't know what's wrong with that.
I just weird, like, I have one rule on the channel when it comes to leaving comments on that, you know?
Just let me enjoy the game on my own.
Don't spoil anything.
That's all I ask.
You can literally literally say almost anything else.
That's the only rule I have, you know?
Of course, don't be racist and all those other bad things.
But that's a given, you know?
That one's obvious.
I like tomato.
Me too!
But only recently.
Most of my life I didn't.
Then I went to Italy and I actually had a tomato that tasted good.
And ever since I liked them.
Isn't that weird?
Okay, guys, I'm going straight in.
The plan was actually to go straight into the game, but I kind of forgot I wanted to do it.
Because then I decided to do the voice thing.
The voice thing!
I had to do it one more time.
All right, let's go.
I'm gonna have to mute this.
God, the music in Isaac is actually kind of goated, you know?
Thank God it is!
Because if it wasn't, man, you're gonna listen to the same tracks again and again and again in this game.
So if you don't like the music in Isaac, that's not good.
I guess you could turn it off, but just saying.
Okay, hold on.
Man, today we're getting another part of this picture.
We're gonna do challenges today.
Not quite yet though, we gotta warm up a little bit.
I also want to try a couple different characters today, but obviously we're gonna start off with Isaac.
This is from now on, the beginning guy.
Either Isaac or Isaac-so.
As they suck.
You know who I mean.
Okay, hold on.
I need to do my pre-gaming stretch session.
Okay, here we go.
I'm ready.
That actually made me dizzy.
Okay, that was lucky.
He's gonna jump over here.
Nice.
Dude, I'm already killing it.
The first run is a good indicator of how things will go for the day, you know?
So this run has to go well.
Just saying it right now, it has to go well.
Let me just have a look in here.
There's no reason not to have a look.
Voodoo head.
Oh, I thought it was... for a second I thought it was the spider mod, just from the visual.
Let's see, sponsored additional curse room.
Oh, improved layouts.
Okay.
Oh, also causes one coin.
Oh, okay.
I think I had that one last time.
No coins for me though.
254 in the machine.
That is alright.
I wouldn't say spectacular, but we're approaching something that maybe smells of spectacularity.
Maybe at 300.
God, don't, don't, don't do it.
Come at me!
How am I gonna deal with you, son?
Good!
Look at that precision sniper gaming.
American sniper.
Greg Hills, or whatever his name is.
Famous actor known for his sketches on Bimio.
Maybe I'm getting that mixed up.
There was a fake baby involved.
I know it.
Kill them all.
My god, that was good.
No!
That was bad!
What is happening?
How did I let myself get murdered like that?
Chip!
I was about to say Jiminy crickets, but I don't really say that.
So why did I have an urge to say that?
What is wrong with me?
Some reason that's only something Americans say, right?
Okay, good.
We're gonna do a no-hit run from now on.
In fact, no hitstream.
I can't even say it with a straight face.
It is so ridiculous.
I'm sorry.
Let's look for these rocks.
There's no rocks.
Yeah, already now it's looking bad.
Actually, do I want to go in there yet?
We haven't found the treasure room.
I don't go in there yet.
No way.
We got poop.
No surprise.
So I think whatever's up there, that is the curse room.
Oh wait, is it?
Or maybe it's the one with the spikes on the floor.
So if I had bought that voodoo item thingy, we could have had two of them, but I don't have the money for it, of course.
Dude, I'm gonna kill the small ones first.
I don't trust like that.
For some reason, my aim is sub-optimal today.
Which is weird, because my aim is usually always on point.
Very good.
Play patient.
That's the way to success.
In fact, patience is probably the most important thing you can have in any video game.
Even action video games.
And if you start to make mistakes, you start to get impatient, because you have to redo things, and then it goes downhill, you know.
So the person that can stay patient throughout any situation is actually the best gamer of all time.
What's this?
It's a new one!
Anemic.
Toxic blood.
We gained some range as well.
Taking damage will make Isaac leave a trail of damaging creep.
I don't like that very much.
That doesn't seem overly good.
I would say, if we had to rank this item, this would be a C item.
C tier.
Now this is good.
Oh crap.
Yo, what happens if I blow up che- oh, those are friendly.
What if I blow up...
Duh!
Huh?
Wait, do I have an item that makes me do that?
I don't know, what just happened?
But I think I like it.
No!
Not the spiders.
Brother man.
Something good.
Man!
What the hell is this?
Alright, blow this up.
Useless.
Give me that.
Alright, moving on.
So now my question is, did we just waste the devil room on this floor by doing that?
We do have zero percent devil chance right now.
Actually, I should have paid attention to what the starting devil chance is.
I'm gonna keep a close eye on that today.
I think it's something to do with the amount of damage you take as well.
I saw that last time.
I had my hands on the wrong part of the keyboard!
It's fixed now.
This boss is easy.
There's no way you can lose to this boss.
In fact, I wonder what my boss statistics are.
Like, are there bosses I've never lost to?
I imagine Duke of Flies.
I don't think I've ever lost to Duke of Flies.
Come here.
Like, just be patient.
You don't have to... Whoa!
Okay.
Yeah, beautiful.
We're gonna get out the way.
We're gonna wait.
One shot, get out.
Easy.
There you go.
Patience pays off.
Seven random coins and one random penny.
Drink it.
The butt penny?
What was that something about farting, right?
Isaac farts when picking up coins.
Destroyed poops are 20% more likely to drop coins.
We are gonna be rich today.
That's gonna be annoying, actually.
Let's go.
No devil room for me, because I think I sort of wasted it by getting it early.
Okay, I do have two keys, but I'm not gonna do that.
Not yet.
No bombs.
I do wonder if I can see... Oh, I can't actually see what it is, except I can't see what it is.
I'm gonna go in here.
Cat ears?
Loki's horns.
Chance to fire tears in all four cardinal directions at once?
Huh.
I'm gonna guesstimate based on my intuition and what I've seen so far that...
Wait, wait, hold on.
Yeah, it's about 20% chance.
That's what I would say.
Maybe 15?
Nah, 20 and 25.
It's gonna be annoying.
There's no other way to do this.
This is the way to do it here.
I'll wait to have range.
Very good.
No tinted rocks in sight.
Wait, what's the difference between green and purple?
Maybe there's no difference.
Ah, we do like poop.
Chance of getting coins.
Like that one.
It's actually so good.
Should I use my key here?
I could also save it and go for that double treasure room or whatever it's called.
Shit.
Okay, that was tough.
That was tough.
I couldn't really do anything there.
This room is crazy.
Okay, this guy is really blue.
High contrast.
Bomb.
Now please give me like a rock now.
Wow, he died fast.
I think he died fast because my cardinal direction thingy triggered at the same time.
And he got hit by multiple attacks all at once.
It is not yet time.
I want to go in the curse room.
Oi, dude.
Got him.
No.
Dude.
Again?
Guppy's tail?
What's this?
The mark.
Oh, the mark!
I love the mark.
Oh, that's gotta be... Oh, but what is this?
Also increased chance?
No, no, no.
Fuck that.
We got to take this immediately.
That is the one that marks enemies, right?
Wait, it's not!
It's different.
Oh, I thought that was the one that marked enemies.
I thought he just didn't tell me in the tooltip and it would show me in the menu.
Huh, what is the other one called then?
Oh, nice, a heart.
Not that I need it, actually.
So, I wonder if I have wasted this room now?
Meaning, can I get it again later?
We'll see.
Man, that's a shame.
Okay, move on.
I got one bomb, I could go in here.
But let's wait.
Oh my goodness.
Dude, I, you know, sometimes you know you're in the zone.
I'm not in the zone today.
Like, I can't dodge.
It's one of those days.
Okay, we got one.
I was not in a flow state at all just now.
I kind of need to be.
I'm looking for rocks, I don't see any.
Okay, so this room is closed.
Too bad.
Okay, I'm gonna blow this up because there could be a key here.
Fuck.
Man.
Well, I guess we can't open that room.
Now, the plan is to get a health upgrade as a reward.
That is the main thing.
I'm gonna go in here.
Oh, go bombs.
All bomb pickups become double bombs?
15 for that?
It's not even that good.
Maybe it is.
I'm taking it.
It's probably okay.
Let's donate.
261.
We're gonna get to 300 today at least.
Okay, I wonder if I've seen all the bosses.
I mean, I get the same bosses again and again nowadays.
Okay.
Oh, okay.
I thought it was cut off.
Come here.
I know you want to come here.
Good.
Booyoyoy.
Get rid of that poop.
Come on now.
Nice.
Oh, massive.
Very good.
Oh, look.
The room is open.
Now, the question is, is it gonna lead back to the same room we were in already?
I'm so excited to find out.
Wait, there's poop here.
It could be money.
Okay, no money.
Oh, it's the same room.
Okay.
Oh, well.
No bombs either, unfortunately.
I could go for this, but why would I do that?
Increases chance of chests as room clear rewards, but also... I mean, that sounds horrible.
No.
No, thanks.
Cheers.
It all depends on the percentages, though.
Give me that.
Uh-oh.
I kind of wish these rooms were set up in a way that you had to fight enemies first and then you get the reward.
Because now I know I'm not even fighting for anything, you know?
I already saw the reward.
It wasn't that amazing.
But if I don't know what I'm getting, I feel like I would fight more feverishly, you know?
More fervently.
Whatever the name is.
On the other hand, you could get an upgrade that would help you in here in the way that it is now.
So, I don't know.
A pushpin.
A chance to fire tears that are piercing and spectral increases with the luck.
Ooh.
So that is definitely, like, combat related, whereas my current item is money related.
I think my current item will pay off more because I have it early, right?
I'm gonna stick with this for now, maybe change it out.
Later, we'll see.
Hold on, I gotta blow my nose.
Okay, let's go.
Oh, this guy wants bombs.
Wait, did I just... There's someone in here.
Or not.
I felt like I just met resistance when I was walking.
Like, I couldn't walk to the right as if there was an invisible creature, you know?
Mess me up a little bit.
Wait, what?
How did that do so much damage?
What is this?
The Emperor?
Oh, nice.
Ah, no bomb.
I don't want to walk in here with my black heart.
That's bad.
No key either, though.
So sad.
I got shots when they died, but it turns out that's not the case.
Key.
Wonderful.
That's a razor.
Blood rights.
Mass enemy damage at cost.
Take one heart of self-damage to gain a tears up and deal 40 damage to all enemies in the current room.
Oh, okay, okay.
Subsequent uses in the same room costs half a heart.
Consumes red hearts before other heart types.
All right.
All right, that sounds pretty cool, actually.
We would need to find a way to heal consistently.
I'm a little scared though.
I'm not gonna walk in there yet.
Hey, bro.
Oi, what?
Give me like at least a millisecond of time when you convert to a skeleton before you shoot the damn thing.
Like it is instantaneous.
That is so hard to dodge.
Oh, he didn't even die.
Come here.
Oh, this is me running from the boulder instead of just going sideways, you know.
Where are you?
Oh, got him.
Dude, this room is annoying.
Wait, is he has a gravity field on him?
What the hell is going on here?
Where are you?
Okay, this has got to be the most annoying enemy in the game.
Not the hardest, just the most annoying.
So far.
Could get worse, maybe.
I don't want to jinx it, you know.
Uh-oh.
Wow.
Wow!
Oh my god, bro.
Nice.
I don't have that much money yet.
What's that?
Cancer.
I like that a lot.
I'm gonna replace it.
Oh, that's beautiful.
You can really feel the difference.
Wait, wait, wait.
I should destroy this poop.
I'm gonna min max so hard, it's gonna be cringe.
Watch.
We're gonna go back.
Now we poop.
Give me that money.
Yeah.
Not bad.
Okay, what do I want?
Uh, I don't know about that.
Maybe a pill.
But this could be like a heart down.
That would be absolutely horrible.
I guess I gotta take this, though.
Hold on, I gotta destroy this.
Money me.
Um, do it.
Fuck!
That was a massive tears down as well.
Fine.
At least I know what that one looks like in this run.
I'm not gonna pick that up again.
In fact, I'm glad I picked it up.
It's like an investment in the future, you know.
It can only go uphill from now on.
It cannot get worse.
That's the way you need to think about it.
Now, I could get in here now.
I'm gonna do it.
What's this?
Consume thy enemy?
Chance to heal half a red heart each time you clear a room.
Oh!
That's really good synergy with the blood rights.
Huh?
But, oh man, we lose the cancer.
I wish I had cancer.
Damn.
Is it really worth it?
I'm not sure.
Oh my god, I got hit!
Okay.
Oh, I can't get that.
Too bad.
There's actually a heal we can take, but I'm gonna go in here.
Oh no!
I gotta do it.
Gopi's color.
Chance to be revived.
Ooh!
That is potentially good.
We need some luck on our side, though.
Give me that.
I am low on everything.
I have zero of everything right now.
Yeah, okay.
Wait, where's the boss?
Oh, I was looking at the completely wrong part of the map.
I thought I was all the way up near the boss room.
I am so lost.
Imagine what I would do with no map.
It's amazing, you know?
It always changes.
Uh...
Hold on, I need to think.
You know what?
I think I would like cancer.
Actually, all things considered, I'm gonna keep cancer.
We're gonna unring the bell.
Bring me the cancer back.
I want chemo, everything.
Thank you.
If that's what it takes to start crying even more, then so be it.
We gotta force those tears out somehow, right?
Okay, let's go!
I'm not gonna use my blood rights.
He has the green poop.
Oh god, don't stand on that.
It's red versus green.
Dude, this is a tough one.
Oh my goodness.
There's too many ants!
Dude!
I'm gonna die.
Like, there's too many ants?
How is this boss suddenly so frickin' hard?
Come on, focus, focus.
Ooh, that was close.
Don't stand on the green goop, you dumbass.
Get out of there.
Fuck yeah, I did it.
That was close, that was very close.
Okay, we actually have a healing as well we could get.
I'm taking this.
Uh, yeah.
Not the best.
I actually hate, I hate these upgrades that have levels to them.
You know, this one, level 1, 2, 3 and 4, I hate these.
Because it is impossible to get more than even 2.
So what is the point even?
With this many items, it's crazy.
Practically useless.
Yeah.
This way.
There it is.
Now, do I want this?
I have zero luck, so I don't think that's a good idea.
I think Cancer is better.
I need all the help I can get right now.
Because right now, I would say the run is not looking too good.
I've killed two bosses so far, and I have not gotten anything really good at all.
Which is kind of a bad start.
We've got a self-harm room, which is horrible.
Wait, what is this room?
There's got to be like a secret in here.
What else is the purpose?
We've got to find a bomb.
Oh, no.
It's not that bad.
It's okay.
Oh, fuck me, dude.
Okay.
Uh, this way.
Oh, what the hell is this?
I mean, my range makes this very nice.
Very happy with that.
Oh, okay.
I got the range.
Let's take it from here.
Nice.
Nice and safe.
That's how I like it.
Oh, man.
Oh, man!
Nah, it's over.
This room is too crazy.
This dude is too fucking crazy for me.
Yeah, kill me.
Unbelievable.
That room was off the charts.
Wow.
Okay.
Another character time.
I think it's too vanilla for me.
Let's do... Oh, wait.
I cannot play this one.
I cannot play... Wait, I thought I had...
No.
I thought that was Magdalene.
It's time for Eulith!
Incubus, Cambian conception.
Let's do it.
Let's do Eulith.
Okay, so let me remember how this works.
Creates a duplicate of Isaac's familiars for the current room.
If Isaac has no familiars to duplicate, grants one demon baby familiar for the room instead.
Okay.
Right.
And yeah, this is like the gimmick.
You shoot via the familiar, and you can duplicate.
So I'm just gonna do it.
Duplicate the crap out of it.
How is it happening?
Wow.
Wait, we have two black hearts?
Oh, I don't like that at all.
This is very bad.
Okay, that helps.
Thank you.
No money, though.
Oh, what the frick is that range?
Okay, I saw that coming.
Don't poop.
Okay, you're farting.
All right, not too bad.
Oh, wait, they're bumps!
They're bumps.
Blow them up!
Hoi-yoi-yoi!
All right.
I could duplicate if I needed, but I don't know if I need it.
Wait, is he shooting against me or my familiar?
No, it's me.
Yeah.
A little this way.
That was nice.
Still no bombs.
And boss is there.
I'm curious to see what this can become, you know?
If I have like 10 familiars, that would be insane.
I'm not going to go in there, not with my black hearts.
There, this is nuts.
Honestly, I think I nailed this room.
The way I did this by going in a circle, I think it was smart.
I think I need to employ that method more.
Come here.
Yeah, very good.
No suspicious rocks that I can see.
Okay, so that is a familiar, right?
A chance to drop a soul heart when taking damage.
A chance to drop a half red heart when kill...
Oh, that's really good.
No, wait, that's not a familiar.
Ha!
I thought it totally would be a familiar.
That is the main thing I want, right?
Familiars.
So if I get that, then I'm rolling.
Take it.
Gotta start somewhere, right?
We're going to go in here and duplicate and go crazy.
Wish me luck.
We don't really need to duplicate against this guy, but...
We may as well do it, right?
No reason to...
Play it risky when there's no reason to.
That was very well said, fuck me!
Okay, good.
This boss is awkward with the familiars.
Okay, nice.
Aww, man!
Don't kill me!
Motherfucker, he still hit me with that.
God, I hate it!
It is so avoidable and I fall into it every time.
I just gotta play patient.
Like I said.
But it's apparently very hard to do.
A hundred percent demon!
Jim.
Oh, wait, we got a tinted rock!
Tinted rock!
But I don't have a bomb.
Oh...
Yikes.
Boink.
Okay.
I'll be back.
Wait!
Oh my god!
Why are there so many?
I thought these guys came out of other guys.
These guys are just on their own.
Very unusual.
Okay.
Oh no.
Not spiders.
This is so incredibly difficult trying to aim with this shit.
Yeah, I mean.
For the best, honestly.
Okay, so is there anything suspicious?
Doesn't look like it.
I think it's pretty much... Yeah, it's over.
I gotta duplicate here.
This is too fucking hard, man.
Small and close spaces with a lot of enemies is just recipe for disaster.
The toenail!
Dropping the trinket will cause Mount of Stomp on its location.
I don't... I don't understand how that would work.
What?
So I need to pick up another trinket mid-combat?
That sounds ridiculous.
That is like the most useless item of all time.
Also, we're totally dead here.
Yeah.
We are done.
I wonder if it's randomized whether or not you have two black hearts with this character, because I hate spawning with one red heart.
It is just almost a guaranteed loss, if that happens.
Yeah, it is two black hearts again.
Fuck!
Man.
If you don't find health upgrades with this character, it's just over.
It's like a sasal.
You gotta find health upgrades.
Let's go up here.
Motherfucker, what?!
I feel like I'm just getting slapped in the face right now.
Like, every single run.
Come here.
Oh, I hate this item.
Better than nothing, I guess.
I mean, fucking hell, dude.
What is even happening?
There we go.
That guy had like five different effects on him.
What is this?
I mean, may as well.
I can't even think of one good trinket.
Maybe cancer.
I'm trying to think what other trinkets are good.
I need a coin real bad.
Yeah!
Nice.
I'm gonna buy this.
Just have a bit of a safety buffer there.
There's also a library.
But I think that requires a key, which I, of course, don't have.
Because why would I?
That would be too easy.
Huh?
Alright.
Um... hmm...
I could go in here.
But I don't think that's worth it.
Yeah, what a bummer of a floor.
Like, everything went shit here.
I'm gonna duplicate.
Dude.
Okay, don't fuck this up now!
Wait for his attack.
Okay, good.
Now we go hide again.
Nice.
Get a couple hits in.
Aaaah!
Thank you!
Yes!
Give me HP.
There we go, baby!
The run has a chance to succeed.
That's what I needed.
Man, that's good.
Finally, no more running around on one HP.
It's pretty much like playing Judas.
If I don't find that upgrade, you know.
Just worse, because you're shooting with your familiar.
Oh my fucking god, how do you even dodge that shit?!
Jesus!
Come here.
Come on.
I thought the bomb just opened the door, but no, that's not what happened.
I still don't have a key.
I don't believe it.
Like, am I just supremely unlucky today with everything that's happening in this game?
What is happening?
Oh my god.
I can't aim with this fucking familiar.
Okay,
we're gonna go down here.
Oh, except with this familiar, I can't use this strategy.
That's too bad.
Hey, there we go.
Frozen is good.
One bomb.
That I can use in a smart way somewhere.
Can I get a key with it somehow?
Because if I can get a key, I can open that door, we get an item, and it's looking good.
If I can't do it, it's not looking good.
I don't know how to dodge that.
Like, you get chased into a corner.
It's not like I can run anywhere else.
Okay, get frozen.
Get frozen.
Oh, there's one more.
Not going in there.
Absolutely not.
Whew.
Wait, why is there a fire there?
Is that bucked?
What about a fire?
That is weird looking.
Oh, it's gone now.
I thought it was like a bucked campfire or something without the camp, you know?
And just the fire.
We're going to have to duplicate here.
I'm going to die here, right?
Just... what is happening?
Hit him.
Good.
Come here, come here, come here.
Fucking fighting for my life!
Oh, key.
Huge.
That means we can get a treasure now.
And we need some HP as well.
There's none.
What is that?
It's a new one.
The inner eye triple shot.
Ooh, that sounds good.
Ah, but less tears.
It must add up to be better though, right?
Otherwise it wouldn't be an item.
I guess there haven't been any purely bad items.
Oh man, the shot rate is really low though.
Okay, that's huge.
I don't have money for anything.
Here, have a coin.
I'm going to save my bomb for next floor.
What am I...
Oh, it's the fucking stuff on the floor, I guess.
Great.
Love it.
Love that fucking creep on the floor.
I was lying, I hate it.
I'm just going to grind out these starts here to get a good item to start with.
I mean, it's the only way.
We got to get the same item we got last time or something similar.
That's like the beginning stage.
If we get that, then we need ideally one more so we can have three hearts.
So we can even have a fighting chance in this game.
Otherwise, there's no point even to continue.
Okay, I'm getting better at the aiming now.
I'm scared of going back to a character that doesn't have a shooting familiar though.
Because I'm going to get... yeah.
It's not going to be good.
I'm going to be used to the other way, you know, and...
It's going to mess me up.
Come here.
What are you doing?
Come on.
Hello!
Okay.
Very nice.
We're going to save that heart.
That is so important.
We kill the boss, we come back and grab that heart.
Random pill, I like that.
In fact, I think I like it more than what I currently have.
Yeah, let's run with this.
I'm going to change it back to the box later on.
Imagine we get a health up pill.
Health up pill plus the eternal heart.
Then we're rocking and we're rolling at the same time.
Okay, good.
Fires.
It does take a lot to generate a pill though, huh?
In terms of mana.
Or battery.
Ah, no bombs.
Damn.
Okay, very good.
This is like the spider run, I guess.
I'm only getting spiders.
Oh god.
Nearly got caught by the spider web.
Actually, there is a strategy against these guys, I just realized.
You can kind of bait where they're going to jump if you get close enough and then you get in position.
And attack where they're going to land.
I don't know if you know what I mean, but...
That is definitely a way to do it.
I feel like I've seen this exact room before with these enemies.
I don't think the game is purely RNG actually.
I think the game has pre-made rooms with pre-made enemies in them.
And then it just swaps out those rooms.
It's a large pool, but I think that's how it works.
Maybe there is a bit of RNG as well within that, but...
Oh, that's a rock we can destroy.
In fact, check this out.
Come here.
Want to bait him over here?
How good is that?
Fantastic, love that.
Ah, I do have treasure room.
Hmm.
I'm not going to get the boss yet, because I need the pill.
Actually, I have five bombs.
I could go crazy here.
I'm going to take this pill.
Is it a blue one?
Okay, I don't know what that one does.
Maybe nothing.
I'm going to do this just to get the bomb back and maybe there's something in the rocks, right?
Doesn't look like it's...
We're not going to pick it up yet.
That happens later.
Let's need a bit more charge.
That was a very good aim.
Very good.
This is a shit shop.
What is that one?
The deck of cards?
Nah.
Man, I don't have enough mana.
There's no batteries either.
Okay.
Let's do the boss.
But before I do, I'm going to switch back to my...
so I can double my thing.
Just for the boss.
This one.
I'm going to let go of the pill.
It's okay.
This is not the pill run, after all.
And I will accept that.
This guy I'm actually going to duplicate against, because he is kind of scary.
Stuy.
Okay, that's good I guess.
How come I can't... Wait.
There's something going on here.
It said I got damage.
Only applies to shots fired from the right eye.
But how does that work for me?
Like my damage number is the same.
Oh well.
Don't mention it.
Capricorn!
Oh, that's really good.
That is really good.
You know what?
I'm happy again now.
I was super sad, but now I'm happy.
What is that?
Prayer card.
Whoa!
Shit!
We need to fly!
Oh, we can't get it.
Unless we somehow find, I don't know, the Bible, actually.
Or something else.
Aw, man!
I want that so bad!
Take these butt flies.
Okay.
Give me that.
At least we have resources this time around.
That gives me hope.
Uh, okay.
You know what?
Why not?
Let's just go for it right now.
I'm going to duplicate and we're going to go crazy.
Luckily, this guy is one of the easier bosses.
He's hard to maneuver against, though, with the familiars.
Damage is good.
Very good, very good.
Solid.
And we can go in there.
But I don't think I'm going to do it.
I mean, I'm going to go in, but ooh.
Sulfur.
Oh, that's... Oh, man.
I thought it was the thing for a second.
What is that one?
Monster?
No.
I don't think any of this is worth it.
The rule is always at least two red hearts, man.
Not happening.
I'm not going to go in yet.
Or should I?
No.
I want to clear a bit more.
Is there any point to clearing more?
I guess I could check out the shop.
I'm going to... You know what?
We're going to try experimenting a little bit with the playstyle today.
Oh, yeah.
So because this exists, we're definitely going to look around, see if we can't find like a Bible or something, you know?
Um, I could get that, actually.
I'm not sure if it's worth it.
Whoa.
There's going to be nothing in any of these.
I just have a feeling.
That's crazy.
Wow.
Okay,
you need to come out of there.
Oh, this room is going to be cancer.
And I don't mean that in a good way.
Oh, nice.
Okay, good.
Very nice.
There is a challenge room over here.
Closed, though.
Dude.
Lucky rock.
Can't drop one penny.
Why not?
May as well take that.
Now...
I'm going to gamble on this.
Great.
Good thing we have healing.
You know what?
Maybe the key to playing this game optimally is to never gamble.
Because I feel like I lose more often than not, you know, when I gamble.
It's like the house is against me.
Okay.
Yoink.
Nothing escapes me.
All right.
Too bad.
Oh, we can go in here.
That's good.
Oh, nice.
We're not going to forget it this time.
This time, though.
This time.
Man, please.
Kill him.
Good.
Dude, what?
How am I supposed to dodge this?
It is insanity.
Okay, that works.
Just get out of range.
But what if I had a small room?
You know, it's pretty much impossible.
This guy is crazy as well.
Wait for him to calm down.
Okay, good.
We're coming back for this one.
Like, how am I dodging this?
Impossible.
Like, this is just impossible.
When you get a combo like that, how are you supposed to win?
Minus 12 streak.
That's a sasil.
Fuck these other characters.
They suck ass.
On this fucking character, huh?
Why couldn't I have gotten that on Eulith?
Look, I pick a sasil.
I get amazing items.
Instant secrets revealed.
Millions of keys.
Why would I play any other character?
I don't understand.
Oh, I have to remember how to play this character.
Fantastic.
I love being able to kill enemies now.
Oh, look at that.
I can just grab that chest.
Ooh, nice.
It's not going to matter.
I can't take damage.
Just flying over obstacles.
I'm not even sure how I just took damage.
Oh, my little guy is shooting.
That's why.
I actually got sabotaged by my teammate here.
Gimme that.
Man, I am not used to playing this.
Yep.
Start over.
We're going to just bang out a thousand runs today.
This is the new strategy.
Just go in there.
Grab everything.
Bob's Curse.
I mean, that's pretty good.
Gimme that.
This has now become an sasil stream only.
There's absolutely no reason to play any other character.
It doesn't make any sense.
They're all going to be empty?
No, no.
This one's going to have something.
What's that?
Amazing.
Extra damage.
I'll take it.
Ah, wait.
This guy's evil.
Oh, thanks.
I feel like the game is getting harder the more I play it.
Like, I swear to God.
I feel like it's getting harder and harder.
Like, even the beginning stages.
Wait, did I just...?
Oh, that's also what that does, isn't it?
Yeah.
Oh, man.
Even better.
Ah, wait.
Look at this.
Oh, no.
Aim it correctly.
Insta dies.
I'm not going to step on that, though.
God, it feels good.
I'm not sure if I should be destroying all the rocks, though.
Like, sometimes they do contain things.
But maybe there's something I need to look out for that tells me, oh, this is the type of room where you need to do that, you know?
Or, oh, I shouldn't do it now, because it would be a waste of time or something.
Come here.
I'm kind of glad I don't have the little follower I had in the last run.
Because I actually got confused a couple of times, thinking I was shooting from the follower, you know?
Didn't help that he was shooting projectiles every time I was clicking the button.
Look at all this damn poop!
The Emperor, amazing.
Wait, what did I have before?
Why won't it tell me?
Why is there no pop-up?
What?
I'm pressing shift, nothing's happening.
Why can't I see it?
Oh, whatever.
No idea.
Go down here.
I'm just going to donate, honestly.
Good.
Wonderful, wonderful.
Slap the boss.
Amazing.
I mean, what the fuck is even going on, man?
Thanks.
What other things did that do?
Two keys, a soul heart, and luck, okay.
I don't think there's any reason to destroy these.
Oh, wait, one more.
Okay, we got to find red hearts, though.
Otherwise, we're not going to get too far.
This is the one downside, but pretty much the only downside.
What does it say here?
I'm going to actually just destroy these until I find something.
Okay,
it takes too long.
If there's a good collection of them like here, then I'll do it.
Like this.
Okay.
There may not be anything in Standard Rocks.
There's got to be, like, some other identifier that tells me that, right?
Pots, on the other hand.
What the hell is that?
Looks like that enemy.
Host Hat.
Places a host on Isaac's head, which makes Isaac immune to explosions!
Chance to block enemy shots and fires... Whoa!
Grants immunity to damage from... Dude.
That is incredible.
Still no tinted rocks.
And I'm looking.
Wait, I shouldn't take damage from this, right?
Yeah, because I got the host hat.
Yeah.
Okay, so notice how a coin came out there when it was exploded?
I think when I destroy it with this, I can't get items, but if I blow it up, it's different.
Unless I'm just really unlucky.
It's possible.
Man, I don't know what to think anymore.
I feel the game is gaslighting me on that.
It's driving me crazy.
Doesn't matter.
We don't need luck with this character.
Just health.
Okay, I have nine bombs.
Watch.
I'm just gonna spawn something here.
Or not.
Wait.
I'm just gonna keep destroying things with my laser and see if anything ever pops out.
That's the test.
Destroy this.
Oh, gimme that.
Okay, we need two more of them, and then something happens.
Something good.
Ah, okay.
I'm not gonna go in there yet.
Four coins only.
We donate.
Just do it.
One more room, and then we go boss.
Oh, I love that.
More keys, why not?
Let's do it.
Oh, it's even the Duke of Flies.
It's gonna be a walkover.
See ya, son.
And health!
There it is.
Should I switch my one health?
For some of this.
Ooh, what's...
Yo, two blue ones and a red for this one.
It's gotta be good.
And Guppy's tail.
Wait, curse?
What do you mean curse?
Oh, right, this was the double-edged sword.
But, I mean, it must have a net positive effect, right?
Otherwise, why is that an item?
Okay, let's take this.
Damage and evil up.
Three black hearts?
Ooh!
Damn, son, I'm actually gonna take this as well.
Wait, what?
Why can't I take it?
Oh!
Okay, there we go.
Weird.
I don't know why that just happened.
Interesting.
Well, I have definitely sacrificed my one red heart for...
Oh man, my character actually looks badass as well.
Look at this.
Holy shit.
I look like the Reaper!
Let's go reap some souls.
Man.
So, this is all glass cannon now.
Full glass cannon style.
Empty?
Okay.
Amazing.
Oh my goodness.
Like, I swear to God, it's like I'm even more lucky when I play Azazel.
I get better items, all my chests are way better, I get lots of keys, bombs, money.
Like, what is happening here?
It's like it's just cursed to play any other character.
This room would have been a nightmare on any other character.
Not in terms of difficulty, just, you know, annoyance.
Nice.
Oh, it's so nice and convenient.
Let's go up here.
I've never seen items dropped from fireplaces on these little islands.
I have a theory that they cannot drop items when they're on a little island like that.
What just happened there?
Was that this one?
What just did that?
Ah!
It was the host hat!
Vlog a shot for me.
Bird's eye.
Chance when firing tears to also fire a sliding red flame projectile.
Okay.
I wonder what that's gonna look like on Azazel.
It's probably just like a single projectile flying out.
Next to my laser.
You know what?
Just donate everything.
I don't really need items.
We're chilling.
We're getting permanent- Oh, there it is.
That's the effect.
Do I take damage?
No.
Oh, wrong way.
Oh, I thought I just turned on the campfire at the end there.
It looked like it, right?
I may have to...
What if another devil deal comes my way?
I'm not gonna be able to resist.
Here, have some money.
Nah, actually.
Goodbye.
Oh, you know what?
I could go up here.
Oh, okay.
Come to me up here so we can blow a hole in the wall.
It's like that DVD logo there you wanna hit the corner of the screen with.
Okay,
so let's see what this rainbow thing does.
What happened?
I was staring at my...
stats, I didn't see anything change.
Fuck.
I must have changed something in the run.
You know, I think it's kind of a modifier that changes something that can happen later on.
You know, now that I got one of these, maybe if you get multiple of them in a row, you increase the chances of whatever good that will happen, will happen.
You know what I mean?
For example, maybe the...
maybe we're gonna get a museum or...
What was that place that I haven't seen but I know exists?
The frickin' uh... the planetarium, right?
Maybe that's what that is or something.
I don't know.
I'm pulling shit out of my ass.
It's just something that changes something in the run.
And I don't know what it is yet.
Bad trip?
I'm not sure.
Oh, that dealt damage to me.
Okay.
Right.
You know what?
I'm gonna be lazy.
Let's just teleport to the boss room.
Oi, yo, yo.
Ow, ow.
Okay.
Uh, nice.
That's huge.
I'm kinda glad we didn't get a devil room.
Otherwise, I couldn't resist.
And it would've been disastrous.
Wonderful.
Moving on.
Oi, yo, yo.
Careful.
I can just sit here.
This is the power of Azazel.
What the fuck is this?
What?
Holy chest.
You've never seen a chest like that.
That is some Omega luck.
A new item.
Daddy long legs.
Daddy's love.
Spider baby.
Familiar that floats high above the room.
And regularly targets and stomps down on enemies.
Oi, I see the shadow.
Reminds me a little bit of the floor master from Zelda.
I wonder if it's inspired by that.
Ooh!
Yeah, that is definitely a long leg we got there.
That can sabotage me, though.
If he decides to destroy one of those things, the bomb's right next to me.
Very nice.
I can just grab that.
Oi, I don't even take damage from the spikes.
Um...
Why not?
Let's just go in here.
I feel good.
The Fallen.
Wait, what?
Crazy.
Uh, goat head.
Guarantees all devil deals.
Ooh.
Mmm...
Oh, yeah, got me a hundred percent demon.
But I'm not done with this floor.
We gotta find some more HP.
Otherwise, I'm not gonna take any devil deals.
It's gonna be useless to me otherwise, you know?
You can't trade what you don't have.
I especially love killing these guys with Azazel.
It is so satisfying.
Oh, it feels so good.
It is amazing.
Get him out.
Okay, Rainbow Worm.
Tears cycle through different worm effects every few seconds.
Um...
Huh.
I'm actually not gonna take it because I have zero keys.
And...
The rusted key allows me to find keys.
Yeah.
We gotta get some more keys first.
Ah, damn, can't even open that.
Damn!
Ah, nevermind!
Theory is kaput.
They do drop items.
Glad I got that confirmed.
Maybe in that room over here.
We're not gonna take damage going inside, so that's nice.
I feel like this room is more often than not shitty things.
Ooh.
Curse of the Tower.
Spawn six troll bombs in random locations around the room each time Isaac takes damage.
Does not trigger from demon beggars or blood donation machines.
Demon beggars!
The ones with the horns?
Does not trigger... what?
Oh, it's not a...
I thought it was a...
card.
Oh, wait.
Wait.
Did we just do a dumb thing here?
Chance increases with luck.
Bombs damage poi- bomb damage poi- so wait a minute.
All my bombs are... poison only?
Because if that's the case, I'm immune to it.
Unless there's an explosive effect and then the poison after.
Bombs two keys.
Oh!
The host hat!
Well, if I'm not immune to the poison, I'm definitely immune to the explosion.
I mean, I'm immune to both, so it's actually an amazing item for me.
Very good.
Ah!
Japriya!
Oh, wait, I'm immune.
I don't need to worry!
Why am I scared?
No need to be scared.
Ah, hello.
Wow.
Okay.
I'm not gonna step on that.
The golden poop we like.
That's very good.
In fact, I think when I think of, you know, luck in this game.
Whenever I mention the whole taking or gambling, I think it is worth it to do when you maybe have more than zero luck.
And if you're below zero luck, then it's probably a net negative.
Maybe that's how I need to think about it, you know?
Let's go to the boss room.
I need to set some kind of rule for myself that if I have below zero luck, then it's definitely gonna be a net negative to do any kind of gambling.
Unless, of course, I can't use my money on anything else and I may as well do it, right?
Ooh, I'm tempted now to do maybe some of this.
Let me see here.
So this one is death's list.
Oh, that's the mark!
Oh, we gotta take that.
I got... Ooh!
No, sir!
Nuh-uh-uh!
Not today!
Man, I have almost no HP.
I'm really kind of setting myself up for failure.
Because I'm very greedy!
Maybe it'll pay off.
We'll see, we'll see, we'll see.
We gotta find just a little bit more healing, and then I'm chilling.
I like this.
I like that!
I don't like that I just did that!
It was an accident.
Wait, they're friends.
I will destroy this.
Yes.
I think I'm starting to understand exactly how this brimstone effect works.
So while the effect is active, it's actually ticking for damage.
I don't know how many seconds.
I guess that's dependent on my tears or something.
No, it's got to be my shot speed, I guess.
In this case, because tears is how fast I charge.
And that's why sometimes the rocks get destroyed late in the animation.
You know what I mean?
Sometimes it's very early, other times late.
Oh, nice!
Please don't be health down.
Okay, that's good, I guess.
This guy, this guy!
No, the footsabble charged me!
Did you see that?
The freakin' foot, man!
Ruined it all!
Don't do it, foot!
Don't do it!
Nice!
What's this?
Purple heart.
Increases chance of encountering the champion guys.
And chance for champions to drop their loot.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, why not?
Oh, that's replacing key, that's fine.
I have a master key now.
I mean, this is just lovely, isn't it?
Stapler!
I don't think that changes anything for me.
Oh, we killed this guy?
Motherfuckin' foot sabotaged me again.
That's actually so infuriating.
Oh, is that a champion?
Oh my god.
Jesus!
Eternal heart!
Uh, we're not gonna pick it up yet.
We're gonna re- wait.
Remember that other one that I should not forget?
Did I forget that one?
The first one I did forget, but there was another one that I ended up...
Maybe... I don't remember.
Maybe I died, actually.
Maybe that's what happened.
We're gonna come back for it anyway.
Uh, where's the next cross?
Or skull?
Alright.
Still no treasure room.
Actually, uh, yeah.
Not yet, not yet.
I need to find a converter.
Imagine that.
Hey!
We gained luck!
As the room reward for doing the marks.
What is that?
Huh?
I don't know what's happening right now.
Uh, what did I get?
It spawns a blue crosshair that summons a ghost that may do helpful things depending on what is targeted?
The ghost can attack enemies, fetch items, press buttons, open most doors, and sometimes steal shop or devil-deal items?
What?!
That sounds really cool!
Dude, uh...
Really?
Hmm.
Let me try.
I'm gonna try and...
Oh, wait.
Wait, did I get it for free then?
I think I did.
I don't remember how much money I had.
It must have been free.
Can I take this?
Well, that's a disappointment.
Let's donate.
Oh, my goodness.
Love it.
Aw, the steam sale I should have got in here first!
Mr. Dolly, more tiers and range.
Ooh, range is so good.
I think I should have picked up the black ones first and then the blue ones, but I didn't think fast enough, unfortunately.
But, this is a very good upgrade.
Extra range is massive.
We need a couple more tiers and then we can go crazy.
Or not tiers, um, coins.
And then we buy that bag as well.
I'm gonna get sabotaged by the foot.
Yeah.
What can you do?
Bathe me in explosions.
Uh, we can almost make a new...
Oh, wait.
Aw, man.
Fuck yeah, dude!
We are... man, there's no way we're losing this run.
This is in the bag.
Like, guaranteed in the bag.
There's absolutely no way.
This is gonna go sour.
Not eating that pill.
I almost did it.
Uh, worms.
Uh, mom?
Oh my god!
That came down fast.
Don't sabotage me, foot!
Nice.
Man, I wish I could get rid of my foot.
I'm actually gonna go in here.
I don't even care.
Uh, this one is the mark.
God damn, I'm starting to remember!
What?
I mean, that's just fantastic.
I'm telling you, Azazel...
You just get more lucky.
It's just better.
No reason to play other characters.
Like, at all.
It's wild.
I'm getting like 10x the amount of discoveries on this character than any other character.
I'm unlocking more things, finding new items.
Uh, wait, wait.
I need to go back inside the challenge room.
Yeah, this is where mom was.
Mom?
Are you gonna be here, or...?
Okay, I guess not.
Huh.
I thought for sure I had to fight that again.
Interesting.
Okay, so we have this weird chest, right?
I'm thinking we can probably use it to dig.
That would be one of the things you can do, right?
Um, oh.
I never opened that chest?
What is wrong with me?
Do we see an X anywhere?
Uh, not that I can see right now.
Let me see what else I could do with that.
Fetch items, press buttons, open most doors, and sometimes...
I mean, it can probably dig as well.
Like, it's gotta be.
Something it can do, right?
Jesus.
Thank god I'm immune to damage from bombs, huh?
Uh, that is amazing.
We love that one.
What do we have here?
Is that...
Little brimstone?
Ouija board, spectral... I mean, I already have that.
The pact, more... ooh.
Two red for two black.
Mmm.
That is really good.
Or I can get both of these.
Uh, no, I think I'm gonna...
do this one.
Actually, hold on.
No, I'm not gonna do any of them.
Because I'm chilling right now.
And there's no reason to have less HP.
Wait, where did you guys...
Did that guy just fly off?
What the frick?!
I found that in a skull?!
Dude!
That is frickin' crazy!
Uh, okay, well...
I like it.
But I'm not done yet.
I need to find a little X on the floor.
Hold on, we gotta destroy all skulls from that one.
Oh wait, for some reason I thought it was an enemy that was gonna come up out of the floor.
Okay, grab this now.
Let's just have a quick look around.
Oh wait, we're not gonna take damage, so don't worry about it.
It's gotta be an X in one of these rooms.
Ah!
There we go!
You ready?
Okay, it didn't do anything, but maybe it's like a chance, you know?
It did say sometimes.
In fact, now that we got the Eternal Heart, we're gonna have an extra heart.
Maybe I'll grab one thing from that room, actually.
Maybe it will take the one that costs two hearts, or the familiar that cost one.
Yeah, I think I'll do that.
Gimme this one.
That's gonna offset the damage or the healing we're gonna get from here.
Let's do this necropolis time.
Oh, I have to remember to kill them in order!
I messed it up already.
I got a mini-me!
Oh, pills.
That's the second puberty, I believe.
Destroy all poops in the room and spawn a friendly spider for each.
Ah!
So that's what infested us!
Now I know!
Cool.
We gotta find a room with a lot of poops.
Wait, what happened?
Did we get an upgrade or something?
Something just said...
Oh,
kill this.
Ooh, I do have a lot of keys.
I have a million bombs, too.
Look at this place!
Alright, man.
I am rich AF.
Wow.
Let's start blowing stuff up.
Nice!
That is incredible.
Man, I can't get in there without using a key.
That's kind of...
Unless this special key allows me to!
Ah!
I thought it was only doors!
Alrighty!
Amazing.
Blow him up.
Dude, 43 coins?
Give me a shot right now.
Wow, we actually killed that in the right order somehow.
Where's the next goal?
Okay, well, I guess we failed it.
The double laser, man.
Is this open?
No, man.
Hold on.
We're gonna try and get in there.
Nice!
Oh, right.
Of course.
Ah, there's no way in there, then.
Okay.
I really thought I just did it.
I messed myself up a little bit.
Man, the double brimstone here is kind of wild.
Uh, not... Yeah, good.
Ah, we killed... We fucked it up.
Wrong order.
What's that?
D10!
Devolved... Oh, that one's good, actually.
But do I... Ah, I think I'd rather...
Wait a minute, I'm an idiot!
Why didn't I use this on the devil deal?
I mean, not that it matters.
I have so much HP, it's fine, but, you know...
You're saying...
That was definitely a bit of an oopsie.
Oh, no.
I can't believe I did this.
Uh, try again.
Like, how on earth...
Mom is not done.
I think.
Wait, what did I just... Oh, locked down?
No, thanks.
Okay, Mom is dead.
Oh, now we haven't infested.
Oh, I see now.
Leave that there.
What's that?
Holy shit, we got three luck!
Have I ever been this lucky?
It's got to be a first.
Mom's ring, oh my god!
Runeshart grants a weaker effect of a random rune?
I don't know what just happened.
Mmm, see, I could use my box on here, but I have so much money, I may as well buy everything.
Fanny pack.
Hierophant.
Donate everything.
Unbelievable.
We're making so good progress here.
The Hierophant was... What was that one?
Was that the one with the two blue hearts?
I think it is.
Yeah!
Starting to remember all these items.
Oh.
Bro, I don't even know what's happening on my screen!
What a mess.
Oh, that was a rock!
I see.
The Hank man, that's useless for me.
I can already hang myself.
Hinky eye.
If I have poison tears, increases with luck?
I mean, this should be really lucky then.
Hold on.
Actually, you know what?
I think I'll keep this.
I want to see more champion enemies.
Here we go!
It's mom.
It's gonna be a cakewalk.
Wait, what is that skull in the center of the screen?
I'm not even sure what just happened.
How did she die that fast?
I don't understand what just happened.
This is how crazy it is.
Absolutely wild.
Go in here.
Sulfur and the false PhD.
This is the good to bad pill.
In fact, you know what?
Wait!
Can we get a battery?
Imagine battery and then again.
But I'm gonna take this.
Actually, hold on.
This is useless for me.
No, it's not.
Yes, it is.
It's an active.
It sucks.
I need my current active.
Now, gaining infinite range would of course be nice, but I don't really need it.
I don't need it.
I need...
There's one heart damage to Isaac.
Turn into a full health pill when at one health.
Oh, yeah, I want bad trip.
That is very nice, actually.
Thanks.
I'm gonna blow you up.
Can I really not fucking blow this guy up?
Three bombs.
Five bombs.
Okay, well, I have so many bombs.
I may as well try it, right?
Okay, we're in the womb.
This is when shit gets real.
Just kidding.
It's gonna be easy with this character.
More speed!
Fantastic.
I mean, I'm full on hearts, man.
I can't even take any more.
Oh, wait.
I didn't mean to push that bomb away.
I'm just gonna find secrets.
No secrets.
Wait, oh, this way.
We just gained 2.5 range.
Just like that.
That is frickin' insanity.
Double Isaac's keys.
Oh!
Damn!
The devil is also incredible.
I'm even gonna go grab that blue heart now, because why not?
Unbelievable.
And we kill...
Oh, did we not do that in the right order, or what?
Nice.
Oh, wait, I destroyed him with my attack, I think.
Oh, you're there.
I really shouldn't have killed him, because I gotta do it in the right order.
But it's too late.
Ah...
Sabotage.
That's the secret room.
You know what, that's not bad, I guess, but I like this more.
Imagine doing this in this room with the mark.
It sounds borderline impossible.
Minus one range, but more damage?
I don't think that trade-off is good for me.
I think it's actually a bad trade-off.
Range means more to me right now.
I'm trying to destroy this stuff.
Use bombs.
Whoa, that releases shots!
Oh, I'm learning something here, so...
Wait a minute.
I'm trying to look for that...
Oh, here, this one?
That releases shots!
Okay.
That's good to know.
Wait, I missed the room.
I was obsessed with those weird rocks.
Or tumors, whatever they are.
Disgusting things.
Sabotage!
Ow, ow, ow, ow.
It hurts my soul every time it happens.
I'm playing a little careless right now.
Is that a lighter?
It's like burn on an enemy when entering a new room.
It removes the tick trinkets.
Why not?
Let's switch it out.
Why is my Familia not?
Oh, my Familia has a little different charge speed.
I see.
That's why they're offset.
I've definitely lost a little too much HP here.
But I don't think it's going to matter, really.
Let's keep bombing.
More rooms down here.
Oh, shit.
Question mark.
Speed up!
Very nice.
All right, I think I'm just going to go in now.
Wish me luck.
It's not going to be luck.
I mean, look at that.
The damage is off the charts.
There it is.
Another question mark.
Lock, clock, damage and range up.
And we unlocked a new thing that appeared in the basement.
Very nice.
Oh, wait, not here.
Wait, they're all question marks now.
Not that it matters.
Grab it for me.
Yeah!
The Book of Sin.
What was that?
Reusable something?
Spawns a random pickup.
Oh, that's useless for me.
I have so many pickups.
Book of Belial.
Temporary damage up!
That one is good!
I can do minus one lock and add damage.
I actually don't mind that.
That's fine.
Okay.
Let me see.
Yeah.
How much damage is it?
Any damage for the current room?
It doesn't say how much, but it's probably a decent chunk.
Okay.
Now it's time for the heart.
Are you a wizard?
No, thanks.
Tears down.
Tears?
No, no, no, tears is good for me.
Oh, I'm so rich!
Look at this!
We're gonna ping-pong between these.
Battery?
Huh?
AAA battery?
Automatically restored?
No, that's not that good.
Two of diamonds doubles the coins?
Yeah!
Let's do one of these as well.
Here, have my coins, guys.
A shark plug!
Using an uncharged item will exchange half a red heart for each missing charge segment.
Uses red hearts first.
Stops working when Isaac is at half health.
No, absolutely not.
Okay, just blow everything up now.
I killed the wrong guy first!
Mistakes.
What about this thing here?
What happens when that gets destroyed?
Okay, that also shoots projectiles.
I did it again.
Oops, I did it again.
Nice, nice, nice, nice, nice.
There's no way I can lose this run.
It would have to be a miracle of epic proportions to lose this run.
What even are these enemies?
Dude, I kind of want to find a shovel so we can go even deeper!
I need Satan!
Gate more range, that's actually so massive.
I guess my money is useless now unless we find the beggars.
Is that Binky?
Soulheart sized?
Yeah, that's good, man.
Make me a baby.
Turn me into a small human.
I didn't mean to enter!
Oh well, I guess we're doing it.
Here we go.
Coca-Cola has been activated.
Dude, I almost have a Brimstone right now with this range.
That's how crazy it is.
Beautiful, beautiful, beautiful, beautiful.
Oh!
Uh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, hold on.
If I open this chest, it's over.
I gotta go in here.
If I open the chest, it's over.
We're going!
Deeper!
A quarter has appeared in the basement.
Shield, I wonder what that actually means.
Oh, even more range, dude, look at my range now.
It's like half...
It's a lot of range.
A lot of range.
Except I have no minimap now, so this is going to be challenging.
I killed the wrong guy first.
Are you going to stop shooting or...
They're not, they're just going to keep going.
I think I got sabotaged.
Yeah, that's sabotaged.
Come on!
Man, nothing good.
Maybe not worth it to do that.
Whoa, what the fuck is that?
Yo, it looked like me!
Did you see that?
Look at this guy!
There's all kinds of new enemies.
Oh!
Joker, teleport to the devil or angel room, hell yeah!
Uh, dry baby, familiar that blocks enemy shots.
Chance to deal instant room wide damage each time it blocks a shot.
The shuttle!
We gotta go crazy!
We gotta go crazy.
Uh, hold on a minute.
Dude, look at all the items!
That's fucking wild!
Okay, hold on, hold on.
Uh, I have two, oh wait, I only have two red hearts.
I don't have that much HP anymore.
I can't be too risky here.
Oh, conjoined is actually a two out of three.
Ooh!
Ooh, that's actually...
Oh no!
Conjoined!
What does that do?
We lost damage on that.
What happened to us?
Oh!
That's what that is!
Okay, I mean, this is nuts now.
We gotta...
We gotta play it safe now.
There's no way we're gonna...
Okay, that was not good though.
Dude, what is...
Why am I dying?
How am I taking all this damage?
Okay, it's actually over.
I think it's over, guys.
It is visually over.
Why are...
There's no stats on it!
Tears up!
Huh?
Why doesn't it say anything?
I don't know what's going on right now.
I just know I'm scared.
And any room I enter could be the end of this.
But you know what?
Even if we die in the next room now...
It was a good run.
And I gained a lot of new items and unlocks.
So I'm happy with it.
Just pre-coping a little bit, you know?
You see how I just did that?
One down, one up?
Tactical.
Okay, that's huge.
Take those.
Wait, there's something on the floor.
Oh god.
I don't know...
What am I taking damage from?
Kill him fast.
Just kill that motherfucker.
Oh god.
Okay.
Okay, dude.
Oh, we are so dead.
We are so dead.
I don't even know where I am.
There's no map.
I'm so lost as well.
This is just not good.
Have I been here?
I have been here.
Okay.
We gotta kill them before they kill us.
Yeah.
I mean, I don't even know where that came from, but yeah.
Good run.
I like it.
Let's go for challenges.
Let's do that.
I can't do the one number four, though, unfortunately.
I would love to take this in order.
But let's do the tank.
Not sure what that is.
But I'm excited.
I see what it is.
We have a lot of HP.
Heels one full, red heart.
Thunder thighs.
Less speed.
Oh, we're really slow.
I see how it is.
0.25 speed.
Okay.
Isaac can break most obstacles by walking over them.
Like a tank.
Bucket of lard.
And infamy.
Chance to block projectiles, because we're a tank.
Oh, man, we're a fatty!
Okay.
This is...
Oh, no!
Get away from me!
Tactical!
That was actually genius.
Get away from me!
Yeah.
He's confused.
He's confused by my E-breaking rocks.
Come on, you can't tell me that wasn't amazing.
Okay, I guess priority is going to be finding speed.
I'm going to break everything.
This is great.
Break it all.
Nice!
Okay, it's totally worth breaking everything.
Definitely going in here.
Uh-oh.
This is going to be questionable!
Okay, the knockback from the tears is actually kind of helping me a lot here.
Flies?
I like it.
Should we become addicted to pills?
I mean, speed up would be amazing.
Okay, I like that, too.
Flies are good.
What is that last one?
Magic fingers.
Consumes a coin to damage all enemies.
Okay, okay, okay.
I don't need that.
Oh, wait a minute!
The glowing hourglass would actually be pretty good.
Yeah.
If I can slow enemies down, you know, to my level, it's going to even things out a little bit.
Let's go in here.
We could actually do this.
We have a lot of HP.
Let's wait until we find some more HP.
We can potentially replace it with later.
Okay.
Oh, I don't want to walk into that one.
It's going to blow up.
Careful now.
Oh, this is going to be terrible!
All right.
Boss is here.
Give me some hearts.
Shit.
Uh-oh.
Yeah, I had to do that.
There was no other way to do it.
Maybe running into the rock up here actually could have saved me.
Okay.
Very good.
That's what I needed.
Show me the good stuff.
I wonder if I can walk into walls as a tank and open...
like, if there is a secret room, you know?
I'm going to keep trying.
I have a feeling that could work.
Let's do the boss, and then we're going to try that thing after.
Oh, wait, I can heal with my item!
What the fuck?
I'm an idiot.
I forgot I had it.
Oh, my goodness.
All right, here we go.
I feel blessed.
Oh, it only heals one.
That's okay.
I don't need more HP than this.
This is, like, twice the amount I normally have on any other character at this point.
So we feel blessed now.
Let's try and figure out what that means.
Oh, the barrels here are going to be crucial.
How the hell am I dodging this?
That's amazing!
Hell yeah, baby.
Yeah!
Beautiful.
A bar of soap.
That's actually massive.
I am now a Bradley tank.
No, what's it called?
An APC thingy?
You know what I mean.
Okay.
Arcade?
Oh, I'm rich!
But I'm going to save my money for a potential shop room, actually.
This amount of money would be crazy not to do it.
Okay.
I have to use my active...
Anytime it's ready, honestly.
Oh no, this room is going to be a little problematic.
I think we're killing.
Can't quite use active yet.
Oh, this room.
Healing.
Blue map.
Reveal secret rooms!
I gotta take it.
Ohoy!
Massive.
Is there a way to blow that up without the bomb?
I'm trying to think.
No.
Don't think so.
Man, nothing?
There's a massive secret room down there!
Why is it so big?
Oh man, I'm so slow.
Oh, what the...
Where'd you come from?
Oh, I spawned them from...
I backed up into a pot.
No problem.
Man, it is so satisfying destroying these rocks.
This challenge so far is amazing.
Like, all the challenges so far have been super fun!
Okay, this is the big secret room.
Well, it's not that big on the map now.
So I don't know what that does.
Okay, that's not good.
That's not good either.
Shit, don't do it again.
Experimental pill.
Okay, well...
That was not worth it either.
That was a shitty pill room.
Yuck.
That was just not worth it at all.
Wait, how did you die?
I didn't damage you.
Where's my tinted rocks at now that I can destroy rocks?
We could go back to...
that room.
No, let's go in here.
Monstro?
Oh, he's the one that jumps.
Okay, I'm thankfully fast enough to dodge that, even though I'm a tank.
Alright, no problem.
My damage is not that great.
Nice.
Clean, surgical.
Nothing to complain about there.
Placenta?
Even more health?
Dude, that one is gonna be wild for me.
The tank that keeps healing.
Huh?
You know what that means.
We're going in that room where we take damage.
God, I wish I was... The backtracking is gonna be painful on this character.
I can tell you that right now.
Yo, could I not technically just cheese the game?
Like, let's say I had that room where I had to step on the spikes.
I just keep healing.
Like, if I just sit around and wait forever.
Bob's curse.
More bombs.
That's actually good for me, because it's hard for me to dodge bombs when I'm slow.
So this is gonna help me.
Well, it's not gonna help me against the explosive damage, I guess.
Only the poison part.
Okay.
You want coins?
You want... Ooh!
Should we try this?
Let's try and give it a lot of HP.
Oh!
Oh, my God!
IV bag.
Portable blood bank?
Feels half heart of self-damage to spawn one of three coins.
Damages red hearts before other heart types.
Oh, so this is just like the portable gambling machine.
It's just a... Yeah, okay.
I mean... Why not?
Wait, what's this?
Oh, right.
What do I want to keep?
I think I keep this one, honestly.
I like being able to just heal.
But then again, the placenta is already doing that.
We could technically gamble forever.
I give this guy coins.
Right?
I heal every half minute or whatever it was.
I generate more coins.
And I think this is the gambling forever loophole.
Except if that happens.
Oh, crap.
Many fly enemies become less dangerous.
That's good.
You need money as well.
Oh, nice.
Beautiful.
What the fuck?
I'm just gaining more than I'm losing.
This is awesome.
Oh, my goodness.
Best gambling session of all time.
A dollar?
99 coins?
What the...
Brother.
Huh?
Plus a h... Okay.
We are rich as fuck.
Oh, I didn't mean to drop that bomb.
Dude, this is crazy.
I guess I don't need to... I have poop on my head.
I guess I don't need the IV bag anymore.
I'm rich, bro.
We're going back to the shop.
Holy shit.
Is there even anything in here worth buying?
The Emperor is good.
That's good.
We can even do that.
We can do that.
Feels good.
Oh, wait.
I'm not immune, right?
Double Isaac's bombs.
Why not?
Great.
Destroy all the rocks.
Wonderful.
Not that I need more money.
Yeah, probably wasn't worth it.
Let's go to the boss.
Dude, we gotta find speed.
Speed is important.
That was a beautiful second floor, if I do say so myself.
I would almost call that flawless.
All right.
I'm gonna wait until I have my blue hearts gone before I go in there.
But I am gonna go in there.
And come on.
These guys are gonna be a pain with the tank.
Oh, wait.
This also... Look!
This generates bridges, too!
Oh, my goodness.
I thought it was only bombs that could do that.
Great knowledge.
Oh, more gambling.
Are you ready, kids?
Experimental pill.
Ah, not thrilled.
Not thrilled about that one.
What the...
I shouldn't have picked it up, actually.
Not yet.
Dude, I am just infinitely rich.
Literally nothing can stop me.
Kite them.
Now I need a shop.
I can't get over there, but I can get in here.
Get him out of here.
Dude, this challenge is so much freaking fun.
All the challenges have been amazing.
Holy cannoli, that's a lot of shit on my screen.
Somehow I'm dodging it all.
That was beautiful.
Now I got a bunch of HP here.
We could actually go back and...
Go to that room now.
The curse room.
Tomatoes.
Uh-oh.
Finally.
Took a while.
Now we explore this region first.
Ow, ow, ow, ow.
Oh, dude, we can totally go crazy in here.
Oh my God, look at all the hearts!
Give me more.
More.
Oh, and we can heal with the...
I'm actually gonna do that now.
Wow!
Holy shit.
Ow!
Oh!
What the fuck?
Uh, hello.
You like, you like bombs?
Oh my goodness.
Dude, you need to die down there.
What's that?
Key piece one.
Increased angel room chance.
2.5% chance to convert red hearts into eternal hearts.
When assembled, it unlocks a special door!
Wait.
We need to keep stepping on this.
Oh my goodness.
Yes, keep healing me automatically, I love that!
Dude, I may actually abuse the shit out of this placenta.
I'm gonna be a real cringy abuser.
Because I am just too...
I'm too curious right now.
Also, we're gonna go up here.
Uh, okay, it's actually okay.
Um, do I take that?
Yeah.
I mean, I gotta leave this room anyway, right?
At some point.
Uh, wait, what's this?
Oh, nice!
Unidentified?
Well, I did have a little too much shot speed anyway, I would say.
Oh wait, so this one charms all enemies in the room.
Now we know that too.
Uh, Emperor, teleport to the boss room.
Teleport to the boss room.
Should I do that now, though?
Oh my god, the key is following me, look!
It's a familiar!
Uh, I'm actually not gonna go back yet.
There's also a secret room down there, I wanna get to that.
Hold on, we gotta go this way.
We should be able to blow this up.
Actually, there's no need.
That's a waste, we could've gone from the room down here.
Also, why is placenta not healing?
When does it happen?
Every minute, okay, I thought it was 30 seconds.
That's not a lot.
Uh oh.
Worth it.
Like, how do I even escape that one?
Oh, maybe I could've pushed it away.
Oh, not the wiggly boys!
Not as the tank!
Come here.
Yeah, I'm rich!
I'm rich!
Let's see.
Habit, recharge this one bar of Isaac's active item each time.
Sure.
No reason not to.
In fact, buy everything.
Strength.
Ah, what does that do?
It just increases damage, I guess.
Thanks.
I'm gonna eat all the rocks.
Charms all enemies in the room.
I think I want strength more.
Yeah.
We healed!
Watch this!
Ah?
Not bad.
Eat all this.
This may be bad.
It's good!
I'm gonna use these.
We're going back to the room with the spikes, dude.
Actually, there is one more room I can do while we wait for healing.
And then we're gonna go in.
God, I'm so slow.
I can't believe we haven't found any speed items yet.
Maybe that's part of the challenge where they can't spawn, you know?
Dude!
Okay.
Thank God.
Oh, I can heal.
I have to remember to use that active effect.
Oh, there's also a healing item over here.
Dude!
Let's go grab that.
Huge.
Let's see if we can get more parts to the key.
Although I have a feeling maybe we need to get the other parts from somewhere else.
I mean, I don't need more money!
But I'll take it, I guess.
I've never had this much money!
Oh, shit.
Come here.
Hey, you like poison?
You like that shit, huh?
You like that shit?
Uh-oh.
Dude, this is gonna be...
problematic.
Wow.
Yeah!
Gimme.
Don't let that be a third.
When assembled, unlocks...
Wait, it looks like the key is fully done, though?
Right?
Oh, I guess they would assemble in my inventory.
Yeah, it's not assembled yet, because it says when assembled, and it's not assembled yet.
So here's the plan, guys.
Oh, first off, do this.
Second, I wanted to take a small break anyway, so I'm just gonna stand here in idle and heal up a bit.
I know it's cringy, but I had to take a break anyway.
So I'll be back in like five minutes, alright?
See ya.
I have returned.
It is such a nice time right now, because it just started raining.
Actually, it's... it's hailing outside.
So there's this really delightful pitter-patter on my windows.
It's really cozy in here.
I also heated up my coffee in the microwave, because I didn't drink at all.
Okay, let's go.
No!
The game was paused!
Dude!
Wait a minute.
I'm gonna go see if I can buy anything else from this shop.
I forgot what I bought.
I must have bought everything, right?
With this amount of money?
What's that?
Oh, right, we have strength.
Ah, damn, son.
I don't even know.
There's also a cart all the way up north.
I forgot what that is.
You know what?
Let's go do the boss, I guess.
I kinda wanna keep stepping on those spikes, though.
Let me see this again.
Increased angel room chance.
Except it says 0% right now.
So what do you mean?
2.5% chance to convert red hearts into a... that's really good.
When assembled, unlocks a special door.
I think we need one more piece.
Although it looks complete, now I look at the key.
So I'm not sure.
Okay, let's go.
I have no bombs left.
Pestilence.
This is actually a difficult boss when I'm slow.
He's gonna start charging me.
Oh, no, this... I may die here.
My damage is too low, I'm too slow.
I do too much blow.
You know, it's a bad combo.
Oh, actually, that was pretty good.
Kill this little guy.
I healed!
Sick.
Oh, it's going pretty well, actually.
Very nice.
Come here.
He's stuck in a corner now.
I love it.
What are you doing over there?
Ball of bandages, let me see.
Mere the block shots and the next one.
Fires charm, chases enemies, has a chance to drop hearts when killing enemies.
I mean, I don't think any binding of Isaac players ever gotten all four of these.
Oh, Eternal Heart!
Very nice.
I will take this, though.
I'm going to go back and step on some spikes, I think.
Because why not?
That sounds like a perfectly great idea.
Actually, before I do, I want to see what this card is up here.
I should have used strength, actually.
Why didn't I use strength in that room?
I was convinced I was going to die in the beginning, I should have used it.
Ah, wait, no, no, that takes... Yeah, I don't want to go in there, actually.
I take damage from that.
The problem is, if this freaking angel guy is going to spawn again, I don't have any money.
I mean, any bombs.
So, I don't even know if I could win.
This is the problem, right?
Yeah, okay.
I guess I'll be back later.
We're going to step on spikes on another floor.
The good news is, we're going to get the Eternal Heart and gain more hearts, baby!
Oh, we can also eat this.
I was just about to go eat this bomb rock.
Imagine losing my Eternal Heart like that.
That would have been disastrous.
Okay, go.
Oh, yeah, there's only six floors when you're doing a challenge.
Yeah, another heart for me.
And the secret rooms are really, really, really, really...
You know what I mean?
It's impeccable.
Uh-oh.
Get out of there.
Wow.
Wait, did my key just block in a projectile?
It is a familiar, right?
Or maybe it was the ball of bandages, actually.
Arcade!
I got plenty of money!
This is the dream!
No.
Actually, I'm going to alternate here.
I'm going to play it like this.
Wonderful.
Min-maxing my arcade gaming.
Dude, getting battery is actually huge as well.
That means I can heal.
Amazing.
Dude, let's do this again.
I'm donating so much blood!
Oh, it's the... Wait, why is this a question mark?
I know what it is.
We've seen it before.
Why isn't that revealed?
Uh...
Weird?
That's weird.
Dude, I still have 78 coins.
I will use all my coins.
You don't think I will?
I will.
Actually, maybe we will find a shop as well.
Uh, okay.
I feel like the battery is battering a little less every time.
I'm actually going to save up two charges of the battery if I can here.
I don't want to use too many of my actives here in case I actually just get a heart from this guy, right?
Okay.
That's not good.
Hey, sick!
Very nice.
Is this guy only going to give me battery?
Or am I just being lucky, so to speak?
I think I'm just being lucky.
Wait, there's yellow and orange as well.
Wait a minute.
Oh!
Nine volt!
Quicker charge!
Automatically restores one charge bar after active item use.
Items with a one room recharge become an automatic timed recharge.
Uh, okay.
Fully charges I6 active item on pickup, okay.
Pretty dope.
Well, we're going to... Dude, this is the ultimate tank experience.
Ohoy!
I love it!
Playing it so safe here.
Can we kill that guy, please?
There we go.
Not sure how the guy up top died.
I'm going to leave this heart for here, or for later, because I'm going to passively heal.
Wait, I took no damage against the spikes?
Was that my familiar?
Wait a minute.
I'm trying to time it, so when familiar is in front of me, I walk in.
Matchstick, that's more bomb.
Actually, yes.
We need bombs.
Very good.
Let's go towards the secret room.
This is such an interesting run.
I need more damage, though.
This will not hold off in court at all.
I feel like I'm wasting my placenta because I haven't taken damage yet.
I've got to go spend some HP on something.
Give me another spike room, man.
I can continue my escapades of self-harm, which is horrible to say, but that's what this game is doing!
Dude, this room is insanity.
Wait, what?
Does the key kill them?
I'm not sure what's happening there.
Also, what freaking door is this key going to open?
The fact that it's a familiar is interesting.
That makes me think I almost need to run into a wall physically.
To have it touch a door or something, you know what I mean?
Oh, we're so rich, dude!
Let's... Oh, wait.
No!
No.
What a waste of a shop.
That is just sad.
Fuck.
This guy is tough when you don't have any items.
Come at me.
Yeah, my key's blocking shots as well, I think.
Yeah, give me more money.
I really need it.
I don't have enough.
Why are you hiding the items, though?
Show me the items.
Maybe he's actually hiding items.
I'm not going to spend my one bomb, though.
That's not good.
I'm going to save my bomb for the secret room, but there's two!
This room is going to be really painful.
Why are they not shooting?
Oh, wait.
Is it because I have the...
I have the skedoodle.
I love it.
Oh, I love that.
Dude, do I need more?
Stop giving me money!
What is this?
Whoa, maximum battery.
Okay, well, I'm full on battery now.
I'll come back.
We got to find a spike room.
I need a bomb, dude.
Many things that I need.
Dude, this key is kind of saving me, it feels like.
Nice.
Oh, the bomb!
Huge.
We're going to break it up here, I guess.
Nice.
More money, of course, because why not?
Can I use the key on you, or like...
Hold on.
They're not combined, though, are they?
Are we actually missing a piece?
It looks like the key is complete, physically.
Like, visually?
That looks like a full key to me.
I'm so confused.
How come the parts are, like, apart in my inventory?
Wait, it's not going to go down?
It's not going to be worth it, then.
Oh, I can't get in!
Aw, man.
But I can go in here.
I will eat your poop.
What's that?
Touch Fuzzy, get dizzy, huh?
That just dropped out of a random mushroom.
Chance to gain a random passive mushroom effect for the room.
Very cool.
Wait, I think he's healing every time he poops.
Could be wrong there.
I think I may take the stick, though, just because I need to get bombs.
I don't have enough.
Oh, I can't get across.
That's a bummer.
What is that symbol down there with the arrow up?
Oh, okay.
It's that room.
What is even going on with that room?
That's the room with the bed, right?
There's definitely... Oh, maybe that's something with the key.
Okay, that was not too great.
I'm actually going to use one of these actives right now, just to, you know, use it.
Uh-oh.
Oh, he's not too bad.
Hey, guys, you want to come closer?
Definitely going in here.
Aw, man.
Wait, can I... Hold on.
Holy shit!
I can't believe that worked.
That is frickin' amazing.
All the things I try now that I have like a million HP, it's super nice.
I'm learning so much shit here.
Where are my bombs at?
I have the frickin' matchstick and everything.
I'm getting no bombs.
Dude!
Dude, dude, dude, dude, dude, dude, dude.
Come on.
That was actually horrible.
Uh, no bombs, unfortunately.
Nowhere.
Which is crazy.
Oh, let's go back to the arcade.
I think there were still things we could do there.
Ah, but isn't that just battery?
That's just battery stuff.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay, well, whatever.
I don't mind.
It's cool.
Oh, wait, we're done here.
Okay.
Nothing else to see.
Too bad I can't eat my way through that door.
I'm actually gonna use this for this fight.
Maybe we get a cool mushroom effect.
Mega Man.
Let's use strength as well.
Okay, that gave me range, damage, and speed.
Not bad.
Oh, wait, what?
I'm not paying attention.
I mean, this boss was pretty damn easy.
Man, why are there no spike rooms when I need them?
Caffeine pill.
Oh, that is so huge for the tank.
And here I thought I wouldn't even be able to get speed.
Whatever.
Eat that.
I guess we're going.
Wait, do we have...
Dead cat, nine extra lives.
That's not good for me.
Ceremonial robes.
More damage.
Oh, dude.
Absolutely.
This one takes three blue.
Wait, what does that mean then?
So right now I have three black hearts and seven red hearts.
If I take this, let's see what happens.
I lose my black hearts!
Yes!
That's amazing!
Very nice.
Grant's brimstone for the current room, activating twice in the same room, grants a more powerful version.
Roger.
That is awesome.
We love that.
Okay.
Although it pains me to say goodbye to the yum heart.
I think it's time we say goodbye.
Oh, seven.
You did, you did me good.
Moving on.
Let's freaking do this, huh?
We're in the depths.
Man, getting that extra speed was huge.
Actually, precision gaming.
Oh, okay, that was not very good.
Man, I lost too much HP.
And that should be it.
Great.
Oh, secret here.
You know what?
I'm not going to use my bomb yet, just in case we have some bomb enemies in here we can use.
Okay, you're going to shoot that.
That's really scary.
Ohoy!
Wait, he explodes!
If I had known that, I would have dragged him to the wall.
That's too bad.
Ah-ha!
Why couldn't I push it?
I couldn't push it for some reason.
That's annoying.
I really tried.
Yeah, I need more money, so why don't we get more money?
I don't have enough.
I must have gotten over 300 coins in this run.
Like, it is bananas.
Oh, no.
Oh, wait, what?
He died?
Somehow he died.
I'm not sure how.
Maybe am I familiar?
Not bad.
Oh, this is going to... Oh, wait, I can destroy rocks.
That's going to be so helpful.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
Calm down!
I healed.
Man, this room is nuts.
Not much room to maneuver and lots of projectiles.
Ah, I shouldn't have done that.
That was...
Oi!
What the... Brother...
Um, wait a minute.
Check this out.
How?!
Dude, the hitbox is way smaller than you think.
That is incredible.
Like, you know what the best part is?
I wouldn't even try any of this stuff if it wasn't for everything that's cumulatively happened in this run.
With the experiments, because I have high HP, you know?
And all the healing capabilities at the beginning.
I feel like these challenges, the best part is actually learning all kinds of new shit.
Because it's forcing me to think about things or try and experiment a little bit more, you know?
We got a shot.
Please don't be like a greed guy.
Ugh!
Wait, can I offer you money somehow?
Okay, you know what?
Yeah, you like this, motherfucker?
You like that?
You like this?
I'm gonna fucking brimstone you to death.
Boom!
Yeah!
Yeah...
That felt really nice.
I have 99 money.
Jesus.
And I spent so much already.
We have a bomb now.
Uh, let's see.
We gotta do the smart.
So the room is here.
So it's like... there?
Oh my god.
I will never recover from this mentally.
Never.
So I'm locked in a corner here, like...
Good thing I'm healing.
Yes!
Bomb me.
More bombs, please.
Okay, let's go try this one more time.
No mistake, arena.
Let me see.
So where exactly is it?
It's...
It's near the top, right?
Gotta be like, here.
Yes, dude!
There we go.
Oh well, um...
That's nice.
Where's my spike room?!
I need it!
Spike my drink, dude.
Just spike it up there.
Uh, eat that guy.
Oh shit.
Dude, these guys are way too fast for my style.
Yeah, that was unavoidable damage.
Yeah, they were gonna spawn these guys.
Dude, this is...
freakin' impossible.
Yeah, brimstone!
I really need more damage, because this is not gonna cut it.
Good thing I can save this item for, um, when it's time for mom.
I'm gonna stone my mom with brim.
Oh, go!
Somehow I dodged that.
Oh, more bombs are so huge.
Oh!
We got the room!
We got it!
Here we go!
Here we go.
Now, I have a lot of healing in one of the rooms back there that I can utilize.
I gotta prepare myself.
I gotta prepare my body in multiple ways here.
That's nice.
We found the healing there.
Very good.
Ooh, we're saving that.
Saving.
Very nice.
Okay, uh, let's see.
Uh, the hearts are back there, so let's just go crazy.
Wait!
It's reset?
Wait a minute, I gotta, uh, hold on.
We gotta double check this.
I'm gonna go grab my hearts.
Oh, it's the mushroom that's affecting my stats, of course.
That's what's happening here.
It's gotta be, like, a net positive, right, to have the mushroom?
Here.
There.
Oh, man, maybe I have to do this all in one spike room on one floor.
I feel like it's the same order, too.
You got a coin?
Nothing?
You feel blessed.
Let's see.
Oh, never mind!
Okay, so there's two blessings now.
Oh!
Ooh, wait, what's this?
Monstrance, purifying light.
Grants a large golden aura that deals damage to enemies within it.
Enemies take more damage from the aura the closer they are to its center.
Dude, this is so cool with the tank!
The tank shall roll over all the enemies.
That is so good.
Okay, let's go back here.
Do I keep stepping?
Ooh, yes.
Okay, now I think we stop stepping.
I'm gonna go grab the hearts back here.
Actually, I could just click, tap, and then have...
yeah.
Oh, I don't need to click, click it now.
Actually, this is kinda nice when I need to navigate, instead of just... yeah.
This is the new way to navigate.
Okay.
Now!
I'm actually gonna clear the rest of the rooms, potentially heal some more HP, and then we're gonna...
go do the step again.
Also, look at this here.
You see these weird lines on the floor, right where I'm standing now?
There's three of them in this room.
I think that counts as a floor decoration...
for whatever that item was that we had last time.
Oh my god, the aura!
It's helping!
Maybe quite a bit, too.
Sup, guys?
I got the aura!
I'm not even gonna attack, I'm just gonna...
Dude, it's so good!
Actually amazing!
Stop the gravity stuff.
Oh, okay then, okay then.
Calm down, calm down!
Oh my god, yes!
The step is real!
Can we step even more?
How come I'm not taking damage from the...
Maybe it's the infamy that just happens to...
help me against the spiky rocks.
It's hard to say.
I got 13 keys, so I may as well do this.
That gave me a coin?
I don't even know what's happening anymore.
Okay, time for the step.
Dude, I love the spike room now!
Spike room is best room.
Oh, that's not...
Fantastic.
Uh oh!
Brim it up!
Can we get another key piece?
Ow.
Oh my god.
Yeah, step in my aura, bitch!
No, okay!
Okay, so the way this works...
You gotta kill... so I killed... how many?
Two angels?
And I got two pieces of the key.
So now I gotta kill two more angels, I think, to get the third piece.
Mmm...
The step is real!
Stevey step!
Come on, let's rip!
We've always still got the fucking brimminy-brap!
I love it!
Briny Sierra!
Come on!
What are you doing?
You're spawning that?
I don't care?
You think your holiness can affect me?
No, no, no!
You're done, son!
Okay, so now, yeah, as expected, no key.
We're grabbing this.
The ultimate step, bitch.
Activate.
Come on.
Actually, hold on, I'm gonna super optimize this now.
I'm gonna go back and grab these hearts.
Just in case we somehow get trouble.
Come on.
Nice.
Oh, careful.
Back up we go.
Ah, actually, I shouldn't have left the room because I could have used my brimstone.
But it's okay, I have another brimstone.
What?
Okay, hold on, I gotta heal more.
Uh-oh.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, we heal.
Good, good, good, good.
I can't get over there.
Too bad.
Wait, boss room is elongated.
I've never seen that.
What the heck?
Before we go in there, we also gotta go back and grab the hearts.
But I wanna just clear these first.
Sir?
Thanks.
Oh, nice.
Healing?
Ah, alright.
Very good.
Ah, right.
Before we step in there...
Man, what?
I guess I could wait for my...
Yeah, the healing.
Oh, it's only half a heart.
It's not even a full heart.
Do I keep stepping?
Let's do two more steps.
Fuck!
Okay.
Why is the angel not coming?
Maybe I already got the full key.
Ooh, is that what happens?
Maybe the key is complete, and there's no more keys to be had.
Um...
Okay, I'm gonna definitely activate brimstone in here, because we're gonna have a bit of a problem, perhaps.
Double trouble!
Oh, you brimmed it up, especially with this range!
Fantastic.
Oh, god.
Get the poop out of here!
Man, the elongated room was actually kind of perfect for my setup.
Yeah!
Breakfast, become even more of a tank.
You love to see it.
Um, what a weird room, though.
Beat the rocks.
Now, I could actually go back and keep stepping.
Woo, woo, woo!
I'm addicted to the step!
Let's keep stepping.
Unless I've exhausted all rewards completely.
What happened?
Something happened.
Oh, no, that was my heart.
Whoops.
Ah, okay, you know what?
I think I've exhausted it.
Yeah, I'm not gonna fucking step myself to death.
The step which has been achieved, we move on.
And I'm satisfied with the stepage.
Let's go.
It's time for Mom!
Let's play Crisp.
We gotta nail this now.
Oh, Curse of the Maze?
Uh, let's go towards the secret room.
I'm actually gonna activate this.
Uh, alright, alright, alright.
Wait, it's- Do I have- Wait, what- Hold on a minute.
My Brimstone is perpetually active.
Do I just have this setup somehow?
That makes me go crazy, Basie?
Hold on, where's the thing?
What was it?
Uh...
Golden Aura.
This one.
Automatically restores one charge bar, actor- Okay, so that's one of three.
And then issues- or fully charges Isaac's active item.
I mean, okay.
Maybe it is actually enough.
That's wild.
I could even step in there.
Oh, I like stepping!
I may like stepping too much.
That's two- That's actually four steps.
Maybe it's too much stepping.
I don't think I'm gonna step.
Let's go in here.
Oh, shit.
The Aura, though!
The Aura's actually kinda goaded here!
Yes!
Uh...
I think I got money.
The Fool.
Oh, secret.
Good.
I could blow you up, but I'm not gonna.
We gotta find a spike room.
I think it's reset on every floor and you can get new rewards.
Why can't I- We gotta step!
Well, we lost a lot of demon points!
By stepping!
Why's that?
I don't like that.
Come on.
Redo something good.
I can't even get past this thing, actually.
Yeah!
Huge!
The rewards are out of control!
Gambling!
Mega gamble.
I
have now become a gambling streamer.
Use the link in the description for...
300 dollars on your first 10 spins.
Holy shit!
Look at me go!
Okay, that was the end of that.
No, it's not!
We keep gambling.
The gamble never stops.
Eee!
Oh shit!
It's okay!
What's this pill?
Yeah!
Speed up, baby!
We love that!
Stepping?
Heal it up.
I'm gonna save that eternal heart.
Of course.
This is random setup, I like that too.
HP up.
Yeah, why not?
Yeah, okay!
Very good.
Okay, I shouldn't have stepped there.
Less tears, I don't like that at all.
A fly orbital, love it.
More range, love it!
Less tears, I hate it.
Wait, this is the last...
Saving eternal heart doesn't make any sense.
Actually, yeah.
Teleport to the starting room.
I don't really want that.
Actually, maybe I do.
Alright, let's go.
Ah, that bomb is ripped, but that's okay.
That's for you guys!
Man, the extra speed with the aura really helps too.
Holy shit!
What do we have here?
Coupon?
Makes one item in the shop or devil room free!
Geez, I like that at random.
Holding this item passively guarantees that one item in the shop will be on sale.
Ah, not worth it, actually, because we're at the very last floor.
I can't believe I actually ended up using all my money somehow.
An unidentified pill in this economy, that's...
Wait, what just happened?
I'm gonna take this.
I'm gonna protect my eternal heart, give me that.
The lovers, that is two hearts!
Dude, we gotta find a step room.
Stepity step?
Definitely.
That's the boss.
I'm not done though.
But the aura...
is wild.
Step into my office!
Some nerds!
They actually get one shot in the inner circle, those little spiders.
Ha ha!
Alright, we're here now.
Did I come from here?
I did.
I don't think I ever went north.
I'm kinda tempted to step on this just for the steppage of it, you know?
Gotta get at least 10,000 steps a day.
Oh my god.
Take it!
Okay.
Okay!
No.
Oh yeah, the fly just immediately disappears.
Cause this isn't the aura.
Finance my gambling addiction, come on!
I can just stand here like this.
Ah, keep going son.
Okay, that's it.
Time to die.
Thanks.
Ah!
Okay, this...
Ow!
The aura does not quite... oh it does reach, okay.
Yeah, the outer aura does not do a lot of damage.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
Just aura the shit out of him.
Good enough.
Okay, I think it's time for the boss.
I wish I could see the map.
Not sure what I missed here.
Also, I'm gonna try and activate this twice in the room.
Because apparently that makes it even stronger, right?
Okay, here we go.
Mod time!
Activate immediately.
But I need to...manifold that, and I don't have it.
Not yet, at least.
Oh, come on.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm not gaining battery, unfortunately.
That's okay, we don't need it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, okay.
But, uh...
What now?
Can I not do anything else?
What about this fucking key I have?
No!
Where's the door?
Fine.
I'll take my victory.
The rune of Anzus has been awarded.
Dude, the challenges are so freaking fun, man.
More.
Oh, the solo system!
This was my...this was the first I ever did.
We're gonna do it again.
Here we go.
Also, what was that sound just now?
Oh, it was probably like a transformation.
So wait, we're flying?
So that means when we go in here, we don't take damage?
Huh?
Good.
Let's do it.
Oh, wait, uh, right.
We don't shoot.
We only use solo system, people.
Moving on.
Oh, man, being able to fly is...
The dream.
Oh, wait, I can't destroy flames.
Oh, that's a bummer.
That one.
Oh, you know what?
The earlier, the better.
We should save up for that.
Wait,
are they running into the fire?
Yo, what?
How come I never see that normally?
It's happened, like, a lot of times already in this run.
And we just started.
The boss already.
Not yet.
Uh-oh.
Fine.
I left the bomb in there.
Unfortunately,
we can't afford this, even though we're kind of close with 10.
I'm tempted to buy a key.
And a pill.
Let's do it.
Okay.
That's good, I guess.
Doesn't matter too much.
Let's do this.
The Duke of Flies versus the solo system flyman.
I like that.
Oh, he's my... Oh, yeah, Flies are my friends!
That's another effect I forgot I had with this.
I don't think this does anything for me.
Yeah, that's useless.
Unfortunately.
Dude, we're gonna... We're gonna own this challenge!
I feel so incredibly confident.
I'm motivated.
I am exhilarated.
I am everything that ends in Aided.
I'm debilitated.
Everything.
Touch my planets.
Ah, you see this here?
Nothing escapes my vision.
I see it all.
This is awkward.
Just a tiny bit awkward here.
It works though.
I should have pushed that bomb.
I still don't have the reaction times to make that decision yet, but it'll happen at some point.
Wait, he's kind of stuck there.
Ew.
Brother.
Okay, you're gonna grow big and strong.
Not on my watch.
Oh, you hit me!
Oh, nice.
Keep an eye out.
Oh, we got the step room!
Stepity step!
Oh, we can't do it though.
We need to find healing.
We gotta find a mechanism to heal.
This is the big decider for this.
Um, wait, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, okay.
Let's go here.
Ah, nice.
I'm taking all of this right into my pocketbook.
Nine coins is respectable.
Oh, what's that?
That looks like something that is kind of fly-ish.
Could be good for me.
As a fly man.
I've seen my fair share of flies.
I've never felt better to fly right now.
Got it.
Yeah!
Back to the shop, babyliciousness!
We're gonna buy this bad boy.
Giant Spi- Oh!
That's amazing!
Wait, Beuzebub.
Three out of three?
Oh, I guess I had that from start.
Blue flies and spiders do double damage!
Fly and spider familiars doing- Oh my-
I cannot die.
I am become destroyer of worlds.
That's right.
I am the solar system.
You shall not encroach on my position.
You shall all die.
Oh god, let's not throw this.
Somehow I'm taking damage.
I don't know how, but it's somehow happening.
Okay, let's calm down.
We're gonna not step today.
We're not stepping.
Oh god.
Yeah, you like that?
You like that?
Dana did a lot of damage.
That is wonderful.
Moms, pearls, more range and luck.
Range is useless to me.
This is great for me.
I can't lose.
Show me the animation.
Nice.
Why is that guy so small?
Was he just born or something?
Oh god, I need to go the other way around.
What an idiot!
Did you see that?
What is he doing?
Step into my office.
Oh wait, go the other way around.
There we go.
Dabolo!
They're my friends!
Yeah!
Sup homies?
Five!
Do it!
Uh-oh.
Okay, you know what?
Next time... Listen.
Next time, I'm gonna bring up a notepad system.
We're gonna note down some shit, okay?
We're gonna note down the spiky boy rooms.
We're gonna note down the the dicey rooms.
We're gonna note down everything.
Because I actually knew that.
This has happened before.
There's no... Oh, he's camouflaged!
Wait, they're all my friends!
Assemble my army!
Holy shit!
More friends!
Join me or die!
Kill them all!
See ya, nerd!
That's cool.
Oh god, I couldn't escape it!
Amazing.
I gotta go a little slower, though.
I'm a little too, uh, in it, you know?
I need to calm down a bit.
Uh, worms?
Yeah.
Unfortunately, I'm poor.
Converter!
Okay, we gotta collect the money, though.
Or bible!
Oh, man!
That is a guaranteed kill on mom!
Whoo!
Some good options here.
Let's find some money.
Oh, come on.
Pop out of your shell.
Okay, a little bit of money.
Not enough, though.
A bit more.
We can go for the boss.
We have all these bombs.
Let's utilize it.
Oh my god, I couldn't see where I was.
Keep him in the blue fly!
Yeah!
Crackjacks!
That's amazing.
Ace of spades.
More chance of finding cards.
I like it.
No devil room, though.
Or angel room, for that matter.
We're not done here.
Dude, solar system is... busin'!
Mmm!
I'm gonna hang out on the ocean!
I got flies, I think.
What do you want?
I can't tell which one is my fly.
Oh, wait, there was no- uh, these- money, money.
Aww, no.
Actually, watch this.
Wow, they died fast.
Pills!
Yeah!
Infested?
Okay.
And something's wrong.
Alright.
Kill him.
Okay, this is a horrible room.
And that's a wrap!
Wrap this, even though it's kind of a waste, but we have to do it.
We're getting out of here.
Nine coins is all we got.
Is there anything I could have gotten here?
Not really.
Yeah, I'm saving it.
That's a shame!
Down we go.
Okay, I think I immediately go in here.
That's kind of sick!
Very cool.
You can reach me, na-na-na-na-na.
Come at me, bros.
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Oh, camouflage!
Oh, he's my friend, okay.
Blister?
Here's an increased knockback?
Uh, well, that's useless for me.
Oh, the stepity step could be real.
I do have a bunch of hearts.
But no healing mechanisms, so that's kind of the situation.
It's gonna chill here.
Beautiful.
Wait, this is the one with the- No, it's not.
What is that?
Duplicates all chests and pickups cannot duplicate Jira or Trinkets.
Okay!
Uh...
All right, I'm saving that.
Oh, god.
Arcade?
Ah...
I don't think so.
Do I have a shop room here yet?
Not yet.
The hanged man?
That's funny.
I have permanent hanged men.
Um...
This way.
Come on.
This is actually kind of annoying.
There we go.
Yes, yes, yes.
Why are they blue and green?
Huh?
Starter dick.
Can hold two cars?
That's kind of a crazy synergy.
With my current Trinkets?
All future card drops are replaced with- or all future pills?
Oh, I don't like that though.
I do like my pills.
I think I'm gonna save it.
Maybe I'll go to the arcade actually.
The arcade has been- has been good to me today.
There's no reason to think why it shouldn't continue to be good.
You know what?
I'm donating money.
I mean...
Health.
Blood.
One more.
Okay, now we go heal.
Now we donate money.
Wow!
We also have one in luck right now.
I mean, I have 20 keys.
At some point, you know, it's too much.
Wish we're gonna find a beggar that takes keys.
That would be incredible.
Hey!
I don't want to waste all my money on this guy.
I also want to do the slot machine.
Well, there you go.
Give me something good.
Nice!
Okay, let's go donate blood.
Get some more money.
This is so good!
Yeah, and now we get more HP here.
No!
Okay, well, RIP.
Let's go collect the hearts.
There's one more heart I can grab, but I don't need it right now.
We're totally chilling.
Whoa!
Calm down there.
Yeah, that was not great.
It happened.
Oh, these are my friends now.
Tomato, guys.
Boss time?
Uh, why not?
Let's go for it.
I wonder if I can duplicate, uh, devil stuff, if we get it.
Oh, crap.
Oh, wow, he died fast.
Cheers.
I don't know if that affects me at all, actually.
I don't think it does.
What's up, guys?
Thank you, and that's it.
That's all she wrote.
Unless this thing is actually open now.
I don't think it is.
No.
Well, I just noticed something.
Look at the left side of the screen.
There's no mom foot.
There's a heart now.
Maybe that means the way to defeat this challenge is to get the heart and not just mom.
It is getting a little harder.
Uh, no pun intended.
All right, let's move.
Actually, we have 12 monies.
Was there anything in the shop?
Okay, curse of the lost.
That's not good for me.
That is actually the worst kind of curse I could get.
Oh, wait, right.
I don't take damage from the creep when I'm flying.
Just another W in the book for Azazel.
All I can think about, actually.
Is there anything Azazel can't do?
Uh, more range, homing shot.
That's completely useless for me.
I can't find my fly.
Oh, there it is.
Dude, I have way too many keys.
Can we give it a key beggar?
Oi, yo, yo.
Stop with the keys!
Na, na, na, na, na.
Come get me now.
Oh, okay.
That was naughty.
Uh, boss is here already.
I'm not ready for that.
There's a dick spot there.
Wait a minute.
Uh, the Jira thing...
Look, it's all chests and pickups.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
Okay!
Brother man!
They have more range than you would think.
Okay, I have a feeling.
Feeling was not good.
I repeat, feeling was off today.
Let's go south.
Wait, I need to check something real quick.
Uh, this thing I got.
Blue flies and spiders do double damage.
Okay, so it's the blue one I need to prioritize.
Weirdly, it feels like the red one is the one that does more damage.
What a weird room.
Hold on.
No way.
What?
That is the most useless room of all time.
I'm starting to doubt my prediction about premade rooms now.
Maybe it is all random.
Okay.
Oh no.
More keys.
The flies become my friends!
That is such a good feeling.
Maybe that's what Beelzebub does, three out of three.
Mother's watching.
Okay, that's the foot.
Friends till the end.
I forgot what that one was.
Okay.
Yeah.
Oh no, it's not even a real shop!
It's fake.
Yeah, come get me then.
Come, come here.
I could just go afk here.
Look at that.
Okay, you asshole.
What is that?
The Emperor... Ooh.
That takes me to the boss room.
Yeah.
I still haven't found a good use for the Jera yet, though.
I gotta find a room with at least two chests, right?
For that to be worth it.
Wait, what's this?
Broken padlock.
Bombs or key?
Wait, what?
Locked can be broken open with bo- Oh, okay.
Okay.
I don't need that at all.
I've got a lot of keys.
Doesn't even matter.
I think we're pretty much done.
Where is the boss?
Ah, damn.
Really wish I had a map.
This was a dead end, right?
Uh-huh.
Oh no!
Okay, uh, more money?
Wasn't there a shop somewhere?
Oh no, that was greed, wasn't it?
It's too bad.
Oh!
Pills?
Yes!
Wait, what?
Oh, right.
It replaces.
Okay, that's not good.
I'm just gonna hide here.
If you don't mind.
Oh wait, you can fly!
Yeah, so where the hell is boss?
The fool.
Oh, nice!
We can get out of here, but then Jera- Oh, here we go.
Jera.
That's how you pronounce that.
Two fools?
Oh, it duplicated that as well, I guess.
I think that's useless for me.
That one is weird.
Ah, deals one heart damage to Isaac, turns into a full health pill when it...
Oh, that's not good.
That's bad.
That's good.
Take this and we get out.
So now, I guess I'm lost.
Guess we'll take that.
The Hierophant.
That's the soul hearts.
Kill these guys.
Oh wait, I can fly.
Ah, right.
It feels like the red flies do more damage than the blue ones.
It's odd, even though it should be the blue ones that do more damage.
Man, these guys are in pain.
Got him.
Man,
this is a one big floor, huh?
Bro, where is- Oh, there it is.
Let's go!
I'm gonna hide in here if you don't mind.
I'm gonna wait until my- Oh, okay.
Interesting.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, not this one.
Ah, it's okay, I guess.
Let's see here.
Money equals power.
Ooh!
Oh, I kind of like that, but wait, is that even- Maybe that doesn't help me at all.
I don't know if this affects my flies.
Strike it, yeah.
None of this actually makes any sense.
I don't think I need to take this.
So, 1.69 damage runs a small damage up for each coin held.
And this one is striking enemy from behind.
I don't think there's a concept such as behind when flies run into enemies.
This is actually completely useless to me.
Yeah, that's unfortunate.
Because I was ready to make a deal.
It's time for mom.
Oh, yeah.
Love that.
Okay, okay, where are you guys?
Oh, that killed his friend!
Not bad.
Yo, sick!
Oh, man, it feels good to have a map again.
That's close, unfortunately.
Some walking around money?
Maybe I'll even donate some blood later on.
Actually, let's do it now in case we get hearts.
Like that.
Actually, a bit more.
Oh!
What was that one?
Increased chance of finding red hearts.
Oh, nice!
Chance to add an additional red heart to chests, tinted rocks, and destroyed machines.
Why can't I scroll down here?
Oh, I guess there's no more to scroll, okay.
I think I like it.
But I'm gonna have to do it like...
Oh, man, it's gonna be in the way.
No, it's gonna be annoying.
I should get a lot of red hearts now, right?
Dude, gambling today has been crazy good.
No!
Okay, that's actually good.
Hey!
I love it!
Spawns three blue flies?
That's good.
And this one is... plus tiers, why not?
I don't think this actually does anything for me.
Weirdly enough, but, uh, yeah.
Uh-oh.
No!
It blew it up!
That's too bad.
Okay, well...
I'm gonna save this a little bit.
Ah, yeah, right, we can't go that way.
Secret is right here.
Another chest!
Uh, exchanges quantities of bombs and keys, okay.
Do I wanna do that?
Yeah, I do.
That's amazing!
The more bombs, the better.
We don't need this many keys.
Hey, guys, I'm just gonna sit here.
No!
Okay, yeah, right, you shoot bombs.
You got that one figured out.
Good for you, good for you!
Aha!
Definitely going in here.
Okay, watch this.
Oh, what a troll!
Bastard.
That is so mean.
This is a giant map.
Yeah, spawn all the flies, please, spawn all the flies.
There you are.
Did we get anything?
A bomb?
There's also a shop here, I can spend my money on that.
Wait, these guys are limited to land?
Oh, I thought they were flying.
That's surprising.
Oh, I just have enough for this.
I'm gonna get it.
Member... Member card?
All shops contain a trap door to an exclusive additional shop.
The special shop sells items and pickups not normally found in shops, but at higher prices.
Oh, no way!
Oh, that's... ooh, that's expensive.
Wait.
What?
It says tarot card?
Following familiar... hmm...
Why does this say tarot card?
I'll be back with more money.
I hope this doesn't disappear later.
This trap door, please stay.
Don't move.
I'll be back.
Ew.
Dude, this...
A horrible enemy.
Money, please.
Nah, not keys.
Although, to be fair, I can't really complain about not finding money today of all days, because I have found a lot today.
Wow.
Hey, friendo.
Oh, no.
Kill him, kill him, kill him, kill him!
Okay.
Ah, that's the boss!
Am I ready for this?
I guess I am.
It's mom!
Man, so far, really good.
This is fantastic.
Yeah!
Synth oil?
I think it's useless to me, man.
God damn.
Oh, wait, I can't go back.
I mean, I don't have any money anyway, so it wouldn't have mattered.
Really wanted to go back to that shop, though, and buy that stuff.
Okay.
Also, I think I forgot to change my...
No, I like Child's Heart.
That's good.
Okay, finding money.
We have a lot of bombs as well we can utilize for combat.
So why not?
Oh, man, they're too fast.
Too dank for me.
Save that.
We do not release the little guy yet.
Oh, he releases himself.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, come catch me now, nerd.
Now we go back and grab that heart.
Oh, God.
What do these spikes even do?
I mean, maybe if I get too close, they lash out at me like a spine crawler.
Oh, wait, I think these guys are timer-based.
Oh, God.
Have you stopped doing that?
Sir.
Not bad.
What the hell is that?
Okay, okay.
That was a waste of a heart.
Shouldn't have done that.
Actually, with this many bombs, let's just go crazy here.
And start looking for secrets.
I think there may be a secret here.
Wait, no, yeah.
Okay, maybe not.
Oh, right here, though.
No, it would be the perfect spot, though.
Nice and smooth.
Or a boar's worm.
Yeah, I don't think this is gonna matter to me, man.
Is it?
No.
It's so weird.
Oh, what the hell is this?
What the?
Oh, it's like a miniboss room.
I see, I see.
It's gonna be rough.
We're making progress.
It's slow, but it's happening.
Ah, I got hit there.
Wait, that was a lot of damage.
That was very nice.
Good ending.
Oh, god.
All right.
Not too bad.
Okay.
Not too shabby.
I think that's good for me.
The smaller, the better.
Okay, for sure here, though.
Man.
Consolation?
Speed, speed, speed.
Yes!
That's wonderful.
Damn.
Boss is here.
Is that the final?
Final?
Is that?
I don't think it is.
I haven't found the treasure room, though.
Let's go up here.
Oh, wait, that's a dead end.
Where's the treasure room at?
I'm going here.
This guy wants hearts?
Hmm.
Maybe.
Depends what I get here.
Okay.
We can have a little bit, then.
Gambling.
Oh, man.
Okay, I'm going to fuck you up.
Okay, start blowing up all the walls.
I'm going to find your secret room.
I'm going to find you.
Huge.
Oh, god.
Wait for them to come a little closer.
There we go.
Tactical gaming.
I'm going to wait a little bit.
Beautiful.
Uh-oh.
One of my worst nightmares.
Oh, crap.
Crap cakes are not delicious.
They're disgusting.
Gimme.
Oh, man, I don't have money.
Okay, blow it up.
What's that?
Monkey paw?
Spawns a black heart when Isaac was used to half a heart.
This trinket is consumed after triggering three times.
Ooh, I do like that, but not yet.
Not yet.
Oh, that's disgusting.
I need to blow it up.
For sure, here.
What?
Wait, where am I?
I'm here.
Okay, for sure on the left, though.
Okay, finally.
It's you.
Uh-oh, don't stand in my own bombs.
Uh-oh.
I'm in trouble here.
I'm in big trouble.
Yeah, shit.
Aw, man, what a way to end that.
Fuck.
Oh, well.
It was a good run.
It's also been four and a half hours at this point.
I think it's confirmed at this point that the orbital mechanics character is the hardest challenge so far.
Because I failed twice on that.
And all the other challenges I've ever tried, I won tried.
So this one was tough.
This was a tough one.
Would love to get more flies to orbit me, though.
Cheers.
But you know what?
I don't mind doing this one again later, because this challenge is super fun.
Oh, yeah.
TRW has the room with Spike Stream.
Man, that was so exciting.
We're gonna be spiking it up later on.
Sheol is basically Hell in Hebrew, by the way.
Okay, I figured it was something like that.
It also sounds like Hell, when you say it out loud.
Write the real XX, Felix.
That is true, that's what I said as well when I was playing the last challenge.
Is that these challenges make me try new things, because they put me in this weird limitation, right?
So I'm forced to try new avenues and experiment a bit more, and it's actually really helpful for me in a lot of ways.
These challenges will help my real runs a lot more as well.
Oh, yeah, I can hold control to drop Trink.
That's true, that's true.
I keep forgetting.
It's weird that it doesn't tell me when I launch into the game, though, like all the other controls.
It really should be there.
If item descriptions don't show on items you saw before, it doesn't save in challenges.
I thought it was like... I thought it had something to do with the fact that you needed to finish the run or something, but yeah.
I guess challenges are a different game mode in a way.
I gambled at least a hundred times today, I think, Divi Light.
At least a hundred.
There was a lot of gambling going on.
And you guys, have you been gambling today?
Who was the biggest winner today and who was the biggest loser?
Let me actually see here predictions.
Oh, Solar System?
Oh, most of you predicted a lose.
I feel like I did super well.
How dare you predict a lose 80% of you when you saw me one shot all the other challenges?
That is some...
man.
I guess I did end up not doing it, but I'm just saying, based on, you know, what happened before that.
Just saying.
It's our challenge.
What can we say?
Okay, okay, okay, fine.
Fair.
That's fair.
It probably went a bit at a hundred percent if I hadn't one shot the other challenges.
Solar System got ants.
I love that meme.
Or expression.
I don't even know.
Maybe both.
All right, guys, I'm going to go immediately, actually.
I'm out of here because I...
I'm going to eat a light meal now and then I'm going to go for my 10K steps.
So thank you for watching.
And look forward to either tomorrow or the day after.
I just got to fix some things first.
A whole new game on YouTube.
Look forward to that.
Thanks for watching.
Bye-bye.